The story until now.
Grumbling about, but not refusing John Matzo's request, Nozomu takes the stage.
Forced to be a boy soprano, he abuses his vocal cords, but exits after two minutes of booing.
At the backup chanson the next week,
he makes a mess of the recital and runs to the Piano Forest in despair, only to find the Comics Forest instead.
A numbered ticket was forced upon him, and the moment he joined the autograph line, the man in front of him struck up a conversation.
The man gasped “In France, manga is called the ninth art”, and other such otanationalism that make up the current fad, leaving Nozomu exhausted.
As the conversation turned to Grendizer's TV ratings,
his number was called and he approached the podium, only to see the artist Shiina going by the alias “Maple Pinpin”.
“What're you up to?” “Well, a lot's happened.” They said to one another,
then began discussing the dark clock tower he had made of rejected manuscripts and raw meat to warn when deadlines approached.
At that moment, a far-off, otherworldly bell rang out. “Run away! The green one's coming!”
Documentary!
Education in Japan
Itoshiki Nozomu
(alias),
Koishikawa Ward
*Voice disguised to protect privacy
Interview with
a current
teacher
Speaking as a teacher, I wonder whether high school is necessary.
Takoyaki
Eat
passing
Bugi-Yobi School
Bugi-Yobi Focused Individual Instruction
Last-Minute Measures
Shin
As an emergency measure, perhaps I shouldn't attend school.
Modern anime
is missing something.
That something is
Rambararu
Meaning
Adult characters
Originally published 1st January, Showa 83.
From Chapter 124
The Emergency which Became a Nun
Well, well. Nowadays...
One's capability for emergency measures is tested!
Capability for emergency measures?
Bugi-Yobi School
Takoyaki
Bugi-Yobi Focused Individual Instruction
Questions
Like how you always end up in a pinch.
A scandal suddenly occurs, and you claim illness and go to the hospital!
Hotel
Adultery!
Sudden
Hospitalization
Next day
Or guests suddenly show up, and you make strange snacks out of fish sausage and eggs!
Hanger
Or enemies suddenly attack, and you fight using hangers found at the scene!
Modern man's
common sense
The kind of capability for emergency measures used to make it through that kind of pinch!
It's impossible for modern man to live without it!
What's wrong with just solving the root of the problem!?
They're emergency measures, so it's fine just dealing with the emergency.
Bugi-Yobi School
Takoyaki
Bugi-Yobi Focused Individual Instruction
Questions
Bugi-Yobi School
Takoyaki
Bugi-Yobi Focused Individual Instruction
Questions
Bugi-Yobi School
Takoyaki
Bugi-Yobi Focused Individual Instruction
Questions
Bugi-Yobi School
Takoyaki
Bugi-Yobi Focused Individual Instruction
Questions
Bugi-Yobi School
Takoyaki
However, your teacher knows quite well that his class is good at this!
A
Yobi School Boogie High
Just today...
It's my birthday!
March 31st
Hidamari
Why do we celebrate birthdays? It is a mystery.
Did you know?
No, it's the first I've heard of it.
San
If you want to see your dreams, pay up!
Fantasy Hangout
Take as many as
the poster.
It's fine, you don't have to do anything.
Come on, we've got to celebrate somehow.
Hold on a minute.
Please do not take the poster.
Tail present.
Hunting.
pak
For when we drink together
Fruit
Here you go.
What do I do? I didn't bring anything either!
Here...
January 20th
Congratulations!
February 5th
September 8th
Congratulations!
June 9th
June 14th
Congratulations!
January 8th
August 7th
Congratulations!
October 20th
May 4th
Congratulations!
October 11th
June 24th
Congratulations!
June 2nd
October 11th
May 4th
January 18th
Congratulations!
Thank you all.
Thank you to Maeda
Good bye to ****.
And to all of the Kumeta fans...
I don't
know what
to do since
it's selling
like this
Zetsubou-sensei
4th season
as a tax dodge
Congratulations!
Presents put forth as emergency measures at school are rather miserable, aren't they?
Isn't just getting something fine?
What do I do? I don't have any presents she'd appreciate, like the others did.
The thought is enough.
I've got it! I can sing!
I'll sing as your present!
Newborn Nami
Newborn
Mama
gave her a cola first bath
that lasted two hours
The other babies
all got barley tea
Sung by Fuura Kafuka (P.N.)
That's more than enough!
Is just getting something fine?
Just as I thought, this class is exceptionally talented at emergency measures.
I didn't find them effective at all!
A
No copying
Death Note
or
Slam Dunk!
No
unauthorized
copying by
students
No
unauthorized
copying by
students
A
Shrink
Zoom
100 copies
Color
Start
Somehow I'll make it through next week's
pairing-specific event with this photocopied book!
Nice emergency measures.
Melancholy of Majiru
Extra
tl;dr
Extra!
Melancholy of Majiru
Countries, OSes, monsters,
department stores, MS girls,
people, etc.
Countries, OSes, monsters,
department stores, MS girls,
people, etc.
Countries, OSes, monsters,
department stores, MS girls,
people, etc.
Lately, there's been a lot of -tans.
Maybe anime companies will be next.
You noob!
I won't give you
contents this good!
Ooh, I'd like to be Kyoto then!
No, that's me.
I was before any of you.
You noob!
I won't give you
contents this good!
What are
you all
talking about?
Well, I'm
a cool X.
Can't you put it politely!?
Teacher, say something!
Well, I'm
a cool X.
What are
you all
talking about?
No, you can leave
Rising Sun and City to me.
Leave the Rising Sun characters to me!
My eyebrows failed.
... Nice emergency measures.
Nice emergency measures!
Plan
That doesn't count!
A friend will be right there
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry for distracting you all by getting wet!
This isn't what makes me interesting!
White Flash
Naked
Festival
I washed all your gym clothes.
If you just put them on, they'll dry out fast.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Recently, I think
viewers don't put
enough effort into
entertaining
themselves.
That really is a common emergency measure.
Just as I thought, my class is exceptionally talented at emergency measures.
Mankind's wisdom lies in emergency measures!
Hurry up with H*H
Recruiting citizens
14 Looks pretty fun.
Author taking a break to gather materials.
This is an emergency measure for when your face shows how exhausted you are.
Face massage techniques you can learn in 10 minutes
Lymph massage
techniques from
the pros
Do it every day, and something amazing will happen
Scenario for Se*a being world #1 again:
* Develop the Game Gear MkII
* Release Saturn games on Archives
* Launch lineup:
Demise Vermillion
Backup Actor
World 2000
Wow, Chiri, you look pretty tired.
Naked
Festival
I wanna rest
I do, don't I?
Yeah.
It's because you're worn out!
I should give you a facial massage as an emergency measure.
Lymph! Lymph!
Japan goes hunting.  Wow, the gunlance is
There you go!
I'm Koyomi
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
What kind of trick is this!?
I'm Koyomi
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
I'm Koyomi
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
I'm Koyomi
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
I'm Koyomi
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
No, I'm Koyomi
Don't make conversations
between people
Teacher, it looks like you're gradually loving women less and less.
Now that I think about it, it seems like the school board is watching me today.
So it's good that your face is back to normal.
The school board is watching us?
nce there's a pachinko machine,
we're waiting for a
new movie or remake
tian Successor Nadeshiko
Oh no, now I've got to be proper and get all dolled up.
Wouldn't it be worse if you did?
Full remake
of Negima
What do I do? I don't have lipstick with me.
The rules were pretty strict at my middle school,
so colored lipstick was forbidden.
I nibbled my lips like this so they'd turn red.
I see!
I've done enough moe anime. I want
to make something that will make oil
wash over my eye sensors.
You're biting too hard!
No time to work
Naked
Festival
Planning to buy:
Gintama / Kinshin
Romance Addition
Steel Expert
Saga 2
Fantasy Hangout
Naked
Festival
I thought it was cold!
The window's broken!
Cold air is getting in!
Let's put a poster over it as an emergency measure!
It's no good! No matter what, the wind blows in!
It's cold!
Don't people play oshikura manju as an emergency measure when it's cold?
Complaints and replies about Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei:
Q: I don't get the jokes.
A: Figure them out yourself.
Q: There are too many jokes.
A: Kumeta has to think of them
all in time for serialization. Have some sympathy.
Q: You swap things in at the last minute.
A: Like pictures of Mt. Fuji.
Q: I want to see a proper show, not a paper clipshow!
A: We are putting all our effort into **-sensei.
Q: This is a nice anime.  Do Lilicure next.
A: Sure, sure.
Q: Come on, make an anime more i
nteresting than Evangelion!
A: No can do!!
I don't need to be Asia's #1
I want to be world champion
Oshikura manju!
Manju is scary
Don't cry, even when you're shoved!
Hold it, that hurts!
Manju is scary
The anko insi
The ank
Th
The anko insi
The ank
Th
The anko insi
A
Urban Legend High
2-VI
A dying message written in blood.
That's an emergency measure when there's nothing to write with, right?
Even if it didn't save his life.
What do we do?
The man from the school board is coming!
At times like these, there's only one emergency measure.
Hide him under the floor.
Won't they think it's strange that Teacher isn't here?
I'm digging,
digging a hole
It's fine. There's a good emergency measure for that.
Japan's defense systems:
ASDF:
Raptors based in Okinawa
GSDF:
Test Unit 2 of
the two-legged
walking tank in
Odaiba can be
sent to the
front lines
GAK:
The Espoir patrols the
Sea of Japan
GSDF:
Test Unit 2 of
the two-legged
walking tank in
Odaiba can be
sent to the
front lines
GSDF:
Test Unit 2 of
the two-legged
walking tank in
Odaiba can be
sent to the
front lines
I see.
Master won't pick up the phone
or return my emails. It seems
like he has me blocked.
But he talks
about me like that.
On kids' TV shows, when someone's being a bad boy, sometimes they replace him with a stuffed animal as an emergency measure.
He probably died after being cut with this accidentally while we were all jostling together.
Huh, there's a name written on it.
Next
Dissolution
Your vote changes the future of the country
National debt \550,000,000,000,000
8/30
I'm sorry!
Feels good man.
2-VI
I've found the man from the school board, but where is everyone?
Everyone's here, just like they should be.
I'm home.
... And that's what happened at school today.
Nebata Hardware
It's nice and warm here under the floor.
Is this what they mean by in-floor heating?
Boss, we've missed the deadline!
Absolutely. Not.
Make
deadline
Damn you, Kumeta!
A white crocodile appeared.
Distributing comics online before their release date is a crime
(for example, Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei)
Strange
If you read nothing but
comics you'll no longer
be able to read kanji
Teacher is marking our tests.
Legend of
the Country
in the Mirror
This is the first time I've seen him do it.
II-VI
Everyone, I'm giving your tests back! Sit down!
Japanese
answer sheet
name:
Kitsu Chiri
Fill in the readings of the following kanji:
Unprecedentedness
Frequent
Wrong human
This was right, but you marked it wrong!
Kitsu Chiri
Right, but marked wrong...
Do they say you'll turn into an anime if you watch too much?
Frequently, for adults,
there are things for which the correct answer isn't right!
If I'm made the butt of a joke, I feel like I've lost
Originally published 4th March, Showa 84.
From Chapter 172
The Right Answer, 30 Years Late
Trouble has occurred
Shoplifting is a crime
Anticipating
Mudatsumo,
Unicorn
Quiz
A*swer X Answer
The quiz show!
What's this all of a sudden?
Our first contestants will be the celebrity team.
Quiz
A*swer X Answer
Don Buriko
Obama / Kobama
Itoshiki Chiru
What proverb involving kappa means the same thing as “Even monkeys fall out of trees”?
Question:
What proverb involving kappa means the same thing as “Even mon—
When they get washed away?
Quiz
A*swer X Answer
What!? Isn't that right?
Run, Takushi
As an answer, it's—
We can't have celebrities answering normally.
From behind you
Sunny Day
Ham it up a little, will ya?
Hey, Producer, don't use him anymore.
Don Buriko
Obama / Kobama
Itoshiki Chiru
Zun
It's the correct answer, but it's not right!
For our next contestants, we have the Businessman Team.
Taira Hitoshi
Aoshima Shinsaku
Ujiie Hajime
Yada Hiroshi
This time, we have a special request from the President.
Go ahead, sir.
Do you know who Da-bleep-go's grandfather is?
Former PM Takeshita?
Yeah...
That's right...
Quiz
A*swer X Answer
Didn't even the President say it was right!?
It's correct.
However, it's not right. In terms of fitting your lifestyle.
You.
Aoshima Shinsaku
Ujiie Hajime
I'm sorry, I don't follow fads.
Is someone someone famous's grandson?
Correct.
That's not even an answer!
Sunny Day
A
Do your
shopping
at Iogi
What a trite program.
Melancholy of Majiru
Stimulus checks, and...
Number 4
Melancholy of Majiru.
Stimulus checks, and...
Number 4
With this,
Japan's economy
will recover too
Majiru, what did you buy with your stimulus check?
I bought DVDs.
With this,
Japan's economy
will recover too
With this,
Japan's economy
will recover too
So, what did you buy?
That'll make you feel better along with the economy.
Interview
Scary Movie
I bought these!
Eh? These aren't anime DVDs.
If you say that-
Adults don't buy anime.
Too expensive.
If you say that-
PFC
Sergeant
General
Chief of Staff
Minister of Defense
Next, the Ministry of Defense Team.
Kitsu Chiri
Otonashi Meru
Kobushi Abiru
Hito Nami
From here on, I'll be asking my class to participate, too.
Which country's submarine violated our maritime
borders around Kochi Prefecture's Cape Ashi-bleep-
misaki and the Bungo Channel?
Which country's submarine violated our maritime borders around Kochi Prefecture's Cape Ashi-bleep-misaki and the Bungo Channel?
The sound of the propellers should give you a hint.
Buzz.
You were there?
Give me your answer.
Chi—
Huh? Anyone who knows anything about submarine sounds agrees it has to be a Han-class nuclear sub!
That's correct, but it's not right.
Tell me why.
Let's hear it from the former Minister.
Ishiba Team
The correct answer is, “It was a submarine from an unknown country, or perhaps a whale mistaken for one.”
Your vote is Japan's correct answer
That was a tough one.
Sunny Day
No, it's common sense.
Next, a silhouette quiz.
Who is this person?
Hint 1: Entered the country with a fake passport
Hint 2: Hung out at a certain theme park
Who is this person?
Hint 1: Entered the country with a fake passport
Hint 2: Hung out at a certain theme park
Buzz!
Jong—
Quiz
A*swer X Answer
That's right, isn't it?
That's correct, but in terms of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, it's not right.
The correct answer is—
That's not even an answer!
Rohto
Pharmaceuticals
A
If you're broke,
better not get
married
Modern Japan has made that the answer!
All right, next question.
An artificial satellite.
Too much cold medicine.
If we have a tax on DVDs we can get money even from those who don't pay income tax.
Put season 4 on a major broadcaster, 5PM Sundays.
No way.
Can you not be so down on that last one?
My dreams will continue
Irrationality where the correct answer isn't right.
McDonal
Saying “McDonal” like your English teacher taught you, but no one understands!
Driving  the right speed (the limit) means you tie up traffic and they honk!
If a customer hyped up to travel asks “where is the ocean beautiful?”, when you answer “Okinawa” they'll feel let down!
Phuket
Rhone
Hyher
Pokke Village
This world where the correct answer isn't right has left me in despair!
Sunny Day
This is a pretty dull program. They should put anime on.
Correct.
Next is the up-down quiz.
Everyone, try to lift Teacher's gondola with your answers!
SHAFT
AD
Tatsuwa
Naoyuki
Itoshiki
Nozomu
Koishikawa
ward
Teacher
Lyricist
Ko
Seitei
What, I'm not asking?
Quiz
All right, question!
Which one sells better, A or B?
A!
Tokyo  Koishikawa Ward
2-VI Team
Even though I was right, he's going down!
A
S2BH
Lyricist
Ko
Seitei
Koishikawa
ward
Teacher
Itoshiki
Nozomu
SHAFT
AD
Tatsuwa
Naoyuki
Yep, this is a "feelings up-down" quiz!
Koishikawa
ward
Teacher
Itoshiki
Nozomu
A
Manic depression
Koishikawa
ward
Teacher
Itoshiki
Nozomu
It seems like, even though it was the correct answer, it wasn't right.
Tokyo  Koishikawa Ward
2-VI Team
At that point, it was a downer.
If she's for real, now, I—!
Everyone, try to answer without bringing the person in the gondola down!
Tokyo  Koishikawa Ward
2-VI Team
Loser
I'm speaking from the loser's circle. Let's interview him.
How does it feel to be a loser?
I haven't lost!
Loser
This was an interview from the loser's circle.
Next, let's take a question from her in the gondola.
Alias
Bureaucrat
Ministry of Culture
Question!
People like me should just die, shouldn't they?
Natsu
Arashi
Tokyo  Koishikawa Ward
2-VI Team
No way!
Alias
Bureaucrat
Ministry of Culture
Many people hold you dear!
Don't give me that, you hypocrite!
You only say that because you don't care about me!
Bureaucrat
Ministry of Culture
Alias
She's going down!
Then...
Alias
If you wanna die, go ahead and do it.
That's horrible!
Alias
I'll really do it!
Either way, she goes down.
Failure
This quiz doesn't go anywhere but down, does it!?
Going up has its own dangers.
Next question after commercials!
Don't change that channel!
Sunny Day
Get Lasik, and you'll be popular with the girls!
Maybe I should get Lasik.
You're fine how you are, Majiru.
A
Koishikawa
ward
Teacher
Itoshiki
Nozomu
All right, time for the next question.
You're pretty far down, aren't you?
This is decisive proof!
With this, we can solve the mystery!
The murderer is the victim's five-year-old son!
That's correct, Zetsubou.
Murder weapon
However...
What are you doing!?
It's true, but it's not right.
Hidamari Baths
If a five-year-old killed his mother, his father would never stop beating him.
Even if he were pardoned, society would make a racket about it.
My response to that is to bring the investigation to a dead end.
Chiri's sis attended this guy's funeral, right?
Sunny Day
He's the fourth out of six brothers.
Cut!
A
TeiTV
Teacher, this is no time to be playing around!
Here
There
Look over here!
Keep saying I want
to do “Focus City”,
but it's out of focus
A time tunnel is opening up!
Let's go!
The heavens revolve around the Earth!
No Solicitors
After all, God placed the Earth in the center of all.
What are you talking about?
Of course the Earth moves.
Heretic!
If you tell people the Earth moves in this era, even though it's correct, it's not the right answer.
You were there?
Always.
Teacher, a loophole!
Midoriyama
Studio
This way, you can avoid being burned at the stake!
I've been saved!
Teacher.
What color clothing is the King wearing?
The King's clothing?
The King is naked.
Otonashi Group
It's correct, but it wasn't the right answer.
Your highness, these are clothes that only Merumeru can see.
Sold!
Isn't this dress wonderful?
Koji! Koji!
He's just some random pervert, officer.
A
It's clothing
that can't
be seen
by fools!
Itoshiki Country Club
Incredible range!
Nice shot!
Well, amateurs may be satisfied with range no matter what their score.
However, in this world, there are times when it may not be best to have too much of a range.
I came today to measure your range.
How much can I break labor laws
How far can I stretch the schedule
How short can I cut my sleep schedule
How long can I put off paying my premiums
How little can I pay for food
How much longer can I keep up this line of work, I wonder
Originally published 4th February, Showa 84.
From Chapter 169
Jeremy Thatcher, Dragon Hatcher
I came today to measure your range.
What are you talking about? Isn't that paradoxical?
Brother, a new course has been completed! Bring everyone!
act
Charsiumen only
Charsiumen Stand
Lessons by Orikin
Takeda
Club
Banpan
Mister X HQ
This is just our town.
Street
Golfer
now in stock
I see, building a golf course in town. That's an easy plan.
Hole 1.
Hole 1
This is the tee for the first hole.
It's just someone's room!
Let's see what this boy's range is.
By the way, this doesn't use balls or clubs.
To Ripru
Ah, he left his room!
Nice shot!
He put on a sweatsuit! Maybe he's going to the corner store.
Shaft Inc.
130m
ahead
Iogi Station north exit
Underground walkway
He got on a train! In a sweatsuit!
Evangeli n movie
Itoshiki
In the end, he went to the theater with a friend!
Miya
Please be
quiet at
the theater
That's quite the range!
The range from home he can go while wearing a sweatsuit!
Speaking of which, this is how you keep score of that.
(double bogey) Taking the trash out
(bogey) Sending a letter
(par) convenience store
(birdy) mass transit
(eagle) theater
(albatross) Ginza
I can only make it down to the corner store!
Hole 2
Hole 2.
Hole 2. That man is the tee.
Let's see his range.
He parked in the middle of the road!
Yes.
He's seeing how far away he can get from his car, having parked in the middle of the road downtown!
Cafeteria
No way! I can't make it out of sight!
Seigu
Maroi
Parako 1
Para
Parako 2
Because they're cracking down.
Hole 3
Hole 3.
Hole 3. A theme park is the tee.
Closing time.
Bus
Taxi
Bu
Maihama Land
nd
Just how far can he make it away from the park without taking those ears off!?
A girl or a child would be fine...
But a grown man can't pull it off.
For this kind of thing, too long of a range becomes problematic.
Like how far an office lady can make it with no makeup!
Home
Office
Hinamizawa
Station
Or how far a salaryman's single-family house in the suburbs is from his office!
Or how far a parent can go while leaving their baby locked in the car!
Parking for pachinko customers only
And there's one especially difficult course I think all men want to try just once.
Hole 4
Hole 4.
February
How far they can make it naked!
That's just being a pervert!
He's made it to the street in front of his apartment!
Nice shot!
He's flying, all the way down to the shopping plaza!
Look at him go!
You've got to call out so you don't hit the gallery!
Fore!
People are avoiding him!
Of course!
Koishikawa
Police
I made it all the way to the station.
Nice, par.
Hole 5
Hole 5.
Meru?
This is a tough course for girls nowadays.
How far can you get without your cell phone!?
That's amazingly short.
She didn't even leave her room!
For this, it's not having much range that's the problem.
What's this?
Brother, you're the tee.
I can't make it any further!
How far can a stalker make it from their target?
Not having much range is a problem here, too!
A
Hogwarts School of
Witchcraft and Wizardry
What?
How far will shut-ins go to buy Jump?
That's not very much range, even for a shut-in.
Give me a break!
I can at least manage a birdie!
To be continued
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Don Buriko,
former PM Takeshita, or Han-class nuclear
submarine is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou-sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Matching the song, let's draw leisurely, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Takagaki Ayahi
Inoue Kikuko
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:    Unita Yumi
Let's despair over the next volume too!