The story until now.
The results from my checkup at a hospital in Musashino were grim.
I have 62 years left to live.
This fact was very difficult for me to accept.
Had I known earlier, I would've left politics and made mistakes
like becoming a host, or a prostitute, or a drug addict.
Had I done that, I would've been more popular with the youth while maintaining this disease.
I looked up at the white ceiling and screamed.
I screamed at the Gods,
“I hate this cruel fate you've bestowed upon me!”
“A disgraceful atheist such as yourself
shouldn't be complaining to them at all,”
replied a nurse that entered the room from behind the curtain.
“Since you're in here, is there a
specific God you wish to worship?”
Ah, of course she would introduce Gods to me, since she's an angel in white!
“Are there any Gods you'd recommend?”
“Sure, I'll give you my recommendations in exchange for all of your assets...”
Just then, another nurse entered the room.
“Hold it. I know Gods that are much better than any of the ones she can recommend.”
Ah, of course this nurse would introduce better Gods to me, since she's an angel in white!
“In dialectical materialism, you'll find an opportunity in death,” she replied.
Then, an unexpected third nurse entered the room...
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
A
Notice
This year,
it's on a
Saturday
I think it's better if you don't open it.
A
Notice
This year,
it's on a
Saturday
If you don't open it, the possibility of you receiving and not receiving chocolate will exist.
Thus, creating a multiverse.
Schrödinger's Chocolate
Schrödinger's cat.
It follows the same principle.
Sch-Schrö... who?
I'll spare you the technicalities.
Basically, you put a cat that might die in a box.
If you don't open the box, the possibility of the cat
being alive and dead will simultaneously exist.
In other words, as long as I don't open my locker,
there's still a possibility that I got chocolate, right?!
I got chocolate!
There's no way in Hell I'll ever open this again!
Aside from putting chocolate in lockers in this day and age,
there are plenty of happy endings that come from opening boxes.
And you'll never know if you don't open it.
But if you don't, the possibilities remain infinite!
It's Schrödinger's forehead.
Forehead?
Back in the day, when I thought my hairline was receding,
I put this box on my head to cover it.
As long as I don't remove it, there's both the possibility that I have hair and that I'm bald!
That's right!
In another universe, you still have a full head of hair!
I guess that's true...
Your hairline's already receding, so
covering it up now is somewhat pointless.
So.
I'd like for everybody to use Schrödinger's experiment and apply it to yourselves.
Schrö...?
It sounds kinda complicated...
Nami, did you get fatter?
I did not!
Denied that quickly.
For Ms. Hito,
[Ten]kappin
Ramen's
Calories
Average
I give you Schrödinger's scale.
As long as you don't remove the box,
the possibility of you gaining and not gaining weight exist simultaneously.
You're lucky.
You have infinite possibilities.
Are you messing with me?!
And for Ms. Kobushi,
I give you Schrödinger's tail.
As long as I don't open this box,
there's infinite possibilities for tails!
In a multiverse, all kind of tails can exist!
Oh, I...
Brought this here last week...
And left it in my desk.
I haven't eaten it yet either...
Is this...
It's Schrödinger's lunch box.
As long as you don't open it, there's the possibility that the contents are edible,
and there's the possibility that new life was born from the contents.
Oh, Mr. Assemblyman.
It's Schrödinger's ballot box.
As long as this box isn't opened,
there's still the possibility that you can remain in office!
You can't bring the ballot box here!
In any case, as long as the box isn't opened, there are infinite possibilities!
I hate to interrupt, but I thought I'd
congratulate Kei on his second marriage.
I didn't know he divorced Yuka...
The stain on the wall.
Kei's Studio
and Storage
This is my new wife.
It's Schrödinger's wife.
As long as the box isn't opened, I can continue having multiple possibilities for my ideal wife!
I wonder what she looks like inside.
I want to know too!
Whoops, the chisel slipped out of my hand!
She's hairy!
Unthinkable!
My ideal wife's possibilities have reduced a little!
You call that a little?
Whoops, they slipped out of my hand again!
She's got beautiful legs!
No! My ideal wife's image is becoming warped!
Brother, what kind of image were you hoping for?!
I don't think humanity is prepared to see your wife!
Teacher, why don't you choose one of Schrödinger's wives?
Pick whoever you like.
They're all boxed-in girls, of course.
You don't have to make puns!
As long as you don't open them up, there's the possibility that you have a loyal wife!
I think I'll know who's inside which box without opening them.
That box is telling you to choose it.
But I don't want this one!
What?!
How about I stuff you inside a box?!
It's Schrödinger's teacher!
Infinite variations of our teacher exist inside the box!
Then,
there's the possibility of there being two of them in the same box, right?!
2-VI
The students in this class are truly an inspiration.
They can be anything!
That's right.
As long as they remain closed, the possibilities for all students become infinite!
Infinite possibilities...?
Then that means
Her hair's split
down the middle-
the possibility of someone existing only to tease, badmouth, and insult me is infinite.
Unforgivable!
Why's the door closed?
It's Schrödinger's classroom.
As long as we don't open it,
there's the possibility that every student will attend class without incident!
Planning
Staff
Budget
Schedule
Quality
Quantity sold
Originally published 10th February, Showa 84.
From Chapter 170
After the Third Time
What are you doing?
I've got a feeling that the third season of this anime won't air.
So, as long as I don't open that box,
there's both the possibility of the third season airing and not airing.
Of course they're going to air it, you wuss!
Fabulously delish!
A
Revision Execution
Freeze High
What'll we do?
What should we do?
Quite the quandary.
The satellite
couldn't
take off, right?
They
couldn't
hear anything.
Originally published 22nd April, Showa 84.
From Chapter 178
The Unburied Secret
This is it, right?
The one in the news.
The missil—
Don't say such reckless things!
The news said that it passed over the archipelago.
So, the JSDF failed to intercept the missile and it fell?
N-No way...
Then what are we looking at?
For now, we should contact the authorities.
Wait a second!
The missile wasn't destroyed and nobody's reported it yet.
This is definitely a national secret, right?!
The government will probably do
everything possible to keep this a secret!
And now that we know their secret, they're gonna make us disappear.
Th—
That can't be...
I-I know!
We should tell this to the media outlets, so the government can't do a thing!
The media...
You think they're reliable?
Besides, this missile fell and it still hasn't been reported yet.
I didn't see a thing.
Me neither.
I saw nothing.
Hold it!
You can't try ignoring something as dangerous as this!
If we do nothing about it,
this could very well end with a bang!
You're absolutely right!
We've ended with too many bangs already!
We haven't had one recently, so it's okay if we do this time, right?
On a side note, I have some great news.
A news outlet is coming today to interview our baseball team.
Why now of all times?!
Apparently, one of the freshmen is an incredible pitcher.
They'll rat us out when they find out!
We have to fool them somehow!
Doesn't it resemble a decoration from an athletics festival?
You're right!
We'll pretend that it's a decoration from an athletics festival.
It'll look more convincing after I finish writing this sporty slogan.
Soaring
You've basically confirmed that it's a missile.
But it's a sporty slogan they use at most athletic festivals.
We have to do better than this if we want to fool the reporters.
C'mon people, think!
Why don't we just flat-out deny it being a missile by writing “Fake” on it?
Fake
Now it looks legitimate.
Indeed.
I don't get it!
Why would you say that?
You don't get it?
For instance, how would these bank
notes look to you if they said “Fake”?
Fake
They'd look legitimate!
It's the same principle.
So, what's our next move?
Let's just bury it.
I-It sticks out like a sore thumb now.
You can tell that something is buried under there.
There's got to be a way to make it look natural.
I have an idea.
We'll think of this as
a natural mound.
My goodness, it does look natural now.
Eh?
They're coming to interview the baseball team, so it's convenient!
Wait a minute!
You can't call this a mound!
I guess not...
The baseball diamond has to be there in order for a mound to exist.
You meant that?
All right. I'll draw the lines around the mound.
The chalk isn't coming out evenly.
Hey, the line's going to overlap into the tennis court.
Emergencies like this take priority.
We'll apologize later.
Brother, there's a problem.
Kim
Instead of concealing it, you've just
determined which country launched it.
Are you kidding me?!
Forget hiding it! What would happen if a satellite were to take a photo of this?!
The mound is rejected!
We have to think of another method!
It collapsed!
We don't have any time left to bury it again!
I know.
This must be a...
Time capsule!
Graduate students buried it ages ago, and it resurfaced due to diastrophism!
Are you deluding yourself?
It's a cassette tape.
I was right! It is a time capsule!
There're probably a few classics on it!
Try putting it in.
This came with it.
So SONY used to be SONV?
Oh, they're singing.
But the quality's so bad that I can't make out the lyrics too well.
Don't you find this tune moving?
I do.
It sounds like they're praising a wonderful person.
Let's pump up the volume!
What's going on?
We're having a festival which celebrates age-old local traditions that encourages national prestige.
And this object is the embodiment of our local deity!
Come everyone, let's all participate in the festivity!
In the promised land lies the flying object.
Bombarding the Earth paradise.
Teacher!
You don't have to lie to them anymore!
That missile really was a fake!
Because the real one is over there!
There was a mistake in the
reading of Mizushima
Takahiro's name in the
article on page 239.
O
Oh
Oh.
Oh..
T
Th
Tha
That
That'
That's
That's g
That's gr
That's gre
That's grea
That's great
That's great.
We've corrected it here, and we
also apologize to the readers
and other concerned parties.
I
It
It w
It wa
It was
It was f
It was fa
It was fak
It was fake
It was fake a
It was fake af
It was fake aft
It was fake afte
It was fake after
It was fake after a
It was fake after al
It was fake after all
It was fake after all.
It was fake after all..
It was fake after all...
So this still ends with a baaang!
Sanosuke
On
time
un
in
ten
tionally.
Originally published 3rd June, Showa 84.
From Chapter 183
Progress in Confinement
Part 2
Ra-men! Ra-men!
Is she okay?
I don't know.
The ramen joint is on the other side of this wall.
All right!
Finally, we've made it!
Naturally, I've purchased this restaurant as well.
Property Purchased
Rub a dub dub, thanks for the grub!
The owner changed, so the flavor changed...
You're the new owner, Milady.
I never saw it coming.
You think you can blow this off with a cheap laugh?!
Now I'm disappointed.
Let's go to a karaoke box to cheer up!
A karaoke box?
If we purchase these properties, we can get there.
You're a high-maintenance classmate.
Boom
Property
Purchased
This is getting to be like the escape tunnels the Medicis built in Firenze!
Wait, why are you guys here?
Our houses were en route.
Your beloved karaoke box is beyond this wall.
Come on, karaoke!
Boo-
Brother!
Rin?!
You were forbidden to go outside!
Speak for yourself.
By purchasing these properties,
Milady has managed to arrive here without leaving her estate.
How forceful...
But I'm safe too.
My legal address can't be at the school.
Officially, I live with Rin.
Identification Card
Itoshiki Nozomu and Rin share residency
You all have to get home though.
We're fine.
Officially, we're members of your household, teacher.
But on an unofficial level.
See   chapter 152   in    volume 16
Anyway, this way, we can go anywhere without breaking the curfew.
I want to go to the sweets shop!
Boom
Property
Purchased
Boo
Property
Purchased
You bought the school too?
Yes. It was en route.
A
Itoshiki High School
All right class, let's begin.
This is horrible.
This way, even if we're under curfew, we can come to class.
I sold the land I bought for that road plan for twice what I paid.
Isn't that just speculation?
Late night, at midnight,
waiting for the night train
Crabwalking on
the cliff-like platform
A life that can fit
into a single suitcase
You, my dear, are
the treasure I chose
Close your eyes and softly whisper
The mantle of Hades will envelop us
You, of all people,
I won't let go on ahead
Let's go on a voyage
Okay, give me your hand
If I'm a slave to my fate,
today's the day I'll
fabulously turn traitor
If death is eternal
I don't care if your holding
on slows me down, let's go
I love you, mon amour
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual missiles that
failed to launch, SONV  or Kamiya
Hiroshi singing the current ending
theme passionately in a karaoke
booth is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou-sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Let's draw using skills befitting of a general.
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
We made a fish cake with the fish we caught.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Tachiki Fumihiko
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Yanyan teaching step by step.
Naughty Ms. Kaere
Yanyan let's study.
Periods one and two are full of bad boys.
But period three has only naughty ones.
The boys have been waiting all night for me.
So repeat after me, 2.2360679.
For tonight's lesson,
I'll be quizzing you on
your serious way of life.
Yin, Zhou, and Qin followed perfection,
while Sui, Tang, and Song followed dignity.
I won't ask for too much,
so don't push it, boys.
On page 108,
recite and praise the great Earthly passions!
We'll swim around the textbook together.
The meeting between music and intellect
becomes a match made in heaven.
They'll leave their mark in history.
Private Lesson!
Naughty Ms. Kaere
Naughty Ms. Kaere!
Finals
My answer was wrong.
What?
My answer for the cone's volume from last week
was wrong.
Because the cones obviously grew more since last week.
Please let me remeasure them!
Noooo!
That's a no-no.
We're not covering the volume of cones today.
A Problem A
Find the volume of
the following cylinder.
Explanation
The volume of a cylinder with
area of base S and height h is
V=Sh
Assuming the radius is r, the
area of the base is πr².
Therefore, the volume of
this cylinder is
5 × 5 × π × 20
=500π
Today, we'll learn how to find a cylinder's volume.
Sorry, you can't get an image just from a diagram.
I wonder if there's a cylindrical object somewhere.
Blackout!
Oh, I found a cylinder.
That's not a very good cylinder, teacher!
The size will keep changing!
His bad habit
is showing
Kumeta
Naughty Ms. Kaere
A
Preview
In order to learn about the habitats of sea anemones, Ms. Kaere took me to the beach today.
However, we encountered the environmental protection group, Zreenpeace.
They pressured Ms. Kaere to wear something smaller since she was wearing petroleum products.
Next time on Naughty Ms. Kaere:
Lesson 119. Greener Swimsuits Will Save the Earth.
Next time
Greener swimsuits Will Save the Earth
How about we bury these balls?
Illustration
Tajima Shou
Let's despair over the next volume too!