The story until now.
In flowery Tokyo lived Nozomu, a spirit medium popular for some reason among the middle-aged.
He was invited to the faraway village Moushiwake-Arima-Son, where all greetings, from “hello” to “good night”,
were given prostrated.
The chief of the village, the name of which means “35-year-old NEET” in Sanskrit, said:
“Something terrible has happened to the maidens of our village.
They have read, and fallen under the curse of, proletarian literature.”
and led him to the inner parlor, where he encountered that which the villagers feared as a once-in-a-century ill omen:
reverse prostration.
It was not that a forward-facing prostration was impossible, but there,
as a statement that he must as a spirit medium open the wrapping paper, he said:
“This is Kemco's CG.”
Drink plenty of Calmotine, and it'll go away.
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
The seniors are having their graduation ceremony.
Back-scratch-
-arat
cards
on
sale
soon
Originally published 18th March, Showa 84.
From Chapter 174
Back-Scratch
What are you getting all twitchy about?
I'm not getting twitchy about anything!
It's not like I'm afraid to go congratulate them or anything!
You're afraid.
I said I wasn't!
Hey, Despair!
Security
Are you some kind of middle-school girl, walking around with that thing!?
Teacher, you're not in charge of the seniors, so it shouldn't matter to you.
More importantly, what's this?
duation Ceremony
In the gym
44th     Teary Graduation Ceremony
A tearful graduation ceremony?
Graduations really are things to cry at,
but if it's written out like this I can't cry anymore.
It seems you understand well.
Japanese can no longer be overenthusiastic about catch copy like this.
Night Watch Room
We're still watching.
Strange
Still watching.
I can't laugh at things called “hilarious” anymore.
Strange
The Interesting
Maeda Show
lolz Kiyohiko
Night
That kind of introduction just makes us skeptical.
44th     Teary Graduation Ceremony
Moving finale
after the
commercials!
Things which bill themselves as moving finales have become unable to move us!
By calling normal citizens pros, we can no longer interact with our neighbors!
Meeting the neighbors is REQUIRED!!
By calling our nation paradise on earth, it feels like it absolutely can't be paradise!
Gov't announcement
The Last
Paradise on Earth
Please study this.
If I have to pick a name for it, it's back-scratching!
Backscratching
Teary
Is probably the best way to put it.
When I was in middle school,
they said that I was an interesting person!
See? No matter what she says, it won't be interesting.
Really.
These are all flashes in the pan caused by media propaganda!
Scratch something's back too much and it becomes unbelievable!
By being overpromoted,
things just get dragged down!
Interesting Comic
Kumeta Koji
Interesting Comic
Kumeta Koji
Interesting Comic
Kumeta Koji
Interesting Comic
Kumeta Koji
Interesting Comic
Kumeta Koji
Stop it!
Seriously, stop it!
Aww, come on.
If you can't carry at least this burden, you won't have a fighting chance!
Won't have a fighting chance?
Over here.
Somehow, we've wandered into a world where everything has its back scratched.
You were there?
Yes, always.
Behold.
Over there is a restaurant that's had its back scratched.
Much-Backscratched
Restaurant
As seen on Brunch!
Great reaction
after mention on Hanakin Data Land
Well, you do see restaurants like this.
A restaurant that's
received plenty of backscratching
A restaurant with plenty of back-scratching...
They're kind of redundant.
A restaurant that's received plenty
of backscratching
We've been waiting for you.
It's had its back scratched plenty, so there should be no problem, brother.
What are you trying to start, Rin?
A game of cards.
Backscratcharat.
Backscratcharat?
The rules are just like Old Maid.
Everyone but the first player to win has to bear the bac-scratching on the cards they haven't discarded.
Why don't we give it a try? Then you'll understand.
Wow, these are really—
Super Zetsubou-sensei.
Super Zetsubou-sensei
Alluring Zetsubou-sensei.
Alluring Zetsubou-sensei
Showa King of Laughing Zetsubou-sensei.
Showa King of Laughs
Zetsubou-sensei
They suck! They all suck! I wanna discard!
Theme Park
Hikomaro
Young Turk
This one sucks too!
This kind of backscratching is the kind of thing that'll get you arrested!
You're drawing some pretty horrible cards for yourself, too.
Asian Beauty Normal.
Asian Beauty Normal
Alluring Normal.
Alluring Normal
Normal of Love and Youth.
Normal of Love and Youth
Super Normal.
Super Normal
Come on! I'm not named “Normal”!
Uno!
This time I really need an inoffensive card...
Theme Park
Hikomaro
Beautiful
This sucks! This backscratching sucks!
Hyper Media Creator Zetsubou
Hyper Media Creator Zetsubou.
Bro, you're so cool!
It's nothing to laugh about, Rin!
If I don't get rid of this card quick...
Take it! Hurry up and take that card!
By the way, there are also tense games taking place at the other tables.
Amongst athletes
This backscratching sucks! I've gotta get rid of it soon!
Fair Robecarl
Domestic
Beckham
Matsuzaka II
Princess **
Prince **
Amongst comickers
This backscratching sucks!
Newcomer Comedy
Social
Commentary
Akiba-kei
Pyramid of Cynical Gags
General of Dreams
Amongst apartment managers
This backscratching sucks!
Rokumeikan
Crystal Chateau
Grand Palace
Residence
Versailles
If I don't discard it soon—!
I'm ending up with more and more backscratching that I can't bear!
These are the kinds of things a middle-schooler would doodle a comic about!
I'm done!
Theme Park
Hikomaro
Big
Bang
Mr. Big Bang!
When he's around, you know something will happen.
Why?
Because he's Mr. Big Bang!
Next week the Big Bang will happen.
No, it'll just be like normal.
I've heard of Mr. “Big Magnum” Kuroiwa, but...
mitsu Tanisawa
Real Estate
Recycling
I can't brighten up.
All this year, my heart's been clouded.
I'm blue...
I'm blue.
School
Why?
Because of leaps.
It's a leap...
There was a leap second this year on January 1st.
It's been irritating me since then!
Thanks
for buying
the opening single
Apple
Picking
Beam
Originally published 14th January, Showa 84.
From Chapter 166
The Adventures of A, Leap, and B
This year, on January 1st at 9AM, a leap second was added.
Why was that second created?
Why couldn't they keep it nice and neat!?
It's just a second, it doesn't matter.
If they didn't mention it, no one would even notice.
No one would even notice?
What's wrong, teacher?
A leap second is just fine.
Compared to how this class may be filling up with leap people!
Leap...
...people?
There's leap years and leap seconds, so what's wrong with leap people!?
They come in without you even knowing it.
Wouldn't the class realize if there was an extra person?
i
Student
Kino
Kitsu
Would they? Really?
Were days or hours to increase or disappear, without clocks and calendars,
just how many people do you think would notice?
But everyone knows in advance!
Do they really?
Leap seconds exist in a careless, spontaneous pattern.
Leap people may well exist spontaneously as if they've been there the whole time!
Well, I get that you're trying to say something philosophical.
There may be a leap person among us!
Strange
Well, in life there are plenty of times when there's one person too many.
Flapper
Fella
When flights are overbooked.
When an editor from Magazine shows up uninvited at a mixer for Afternoon.
When an amateur decides to show up for ADR.
It's extremely likely that those phenomena are the work of leap people!
Teacher.
Oh no, teacher!
You were there?
Yes, always.
It appears that leap people infest even shopping arcades.
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Karaoke Cafe
Sale
Are you okay?
Ark
Sale
Cupa
Ramen
\100
Th—the number of people increased!
One per customer
first 40 customers
as advertised
eggs
One per customer
first 40 customers
as advertised
eggs
One per customer
first 40 customers
as advertised
eggs
There were 40 packs, one per customer,
but they were taken up by only 39 people!
Wow, that's scary!
It must have been the work of the leap people!
Didn't someone just come through the line twice?
I saw one!
Cheap
Halogen
Heater
1 per
customer
A
-sho Electronics
Bldg.
A
Clearance
Sale
S
A leap person was in the elevator!
Bldg.
In the elevator with an occupancy limit of 5!
Maximum occupancy 5
There were only five people riding, but the overweight buzzer went off!
A
-sho Electronics
Cheap
Halogen
Heater
1 per
customer
A
-nasho Electronics
-da
Bldg.
A
Clearance
Sale
Cafe
Up to
There had to be a leap person on board!
Well, ummm, that's...
A
-nasho Electronics
Leap people can occur in groups, too!
A
nald's
Great
Value
AA
Sale
And they carry out a vital role in Japan's economy!
Just yesterday...
Orix VS Rakuten
Today's attendance is 55,000.
Gate 20
50,000, with that many empty seats!?
Obviously, leap people came to watch.
McRonald's
\100
Burger
Super
Mega Jumbo
Value Meal
\850
Free
with
coupon
Up to
Sale
Ram     Trading
McRonald's
Er...
Top 5 chart
weekly ranking as of the 14th
For CDs that no one buys to top the Oricon charts,
masses of leap people must be buying them!
No, that's—
McRonald's
Rambo Trading
For the organizers to claim 110,000 when only 2000 people showed up,
Freedom
Protest
Profest
108,000 leap people must have participated!
Protest
Leap people support Japan from the shadows!
Cleaning
Stationery
karao
Dry Cleaning
Leather
Coats
School
gym
uniforms
S/M/L
in stock
Cleaning
Stationery
karao
Dry Cleaning
Leather
Coats
School
gym
uniforms
S/M/L
in stock
Cleaning
karao
Dry Cleaning
Leather
Coats
Cleaning
karao
Dry Cleaning
Leather
Coats
Cleaning
karao
Dry Cleaning
Leather
Coats
Cleaning
karao
Dry Cleaning
Leather
Coats
Leap seconds irritate me enough.
Now there's leap people?
And in groups?
I'll cut them back down to the proper number!
Mandara
Hold it!
Fu-Man
Chiri, you might be a leap person!
We Buy
Me!?
That's stupid!
Aninight
We Buy High
Mandara
Try to remember, Chiri!
Happy Birthday,Saorin
Happy birthday to you!
Oh my, you only invited five, but one more of your friends showed up.
A girl I didn't invite came.
Coming along on a friend's date.
Going along with a friend to the salon, and not getting a trim, just waiting and reading comics.
We can suspect you of being a leap person!
stationery
No way!
Cake sliced a little too thin
Because someone extra showed up
Reducing the number of mouths to feed is a sin
Stone chirashi-zushi
Then won't you join our group?
Who are you?
We're the Leap Man Group.
THE LEAP MAN
Live
Just what is this?
Don't you know?
It's the Leap Man Group, popular among subculture-loving coeds.
Look, more members are coming out.
A baseball player's second wife. A leap wife!
Second
marriage
The leap members of an idol group that grew too big!
A leap superstar who's in Milan now for some reason!
And it's not just limited to people and time; there's leap everything!
Even the secondhand goods that they use!
Leap magazines that get overprinted even though magazines don't sell anymore!
Sirius
Things that you can't imagine coming out on Bluray are Leap-Ray Discs!
Ami
Suzuki
Leap menus, posted in cafes even though you can't order from them!
Chive Napolitan
Chive Steak
Chive Bowl
Leap things are everywhere!
And here comes their specialty!
A physical performance!
A long hair that grew somewhere weird; a leap hair!
A third eye that appears after much training; a leap eye!
Using an audience member!?
They put Hito on stage!
What kind of leap thing does she have?
Leap guts.
Leap guts?
I don't have that kind of excess internal organ!
Koishikawa Rescue
Tamif
It's her appendix.
Well, you can't say you don't have leap guts.
Tamif
How normal.
Don't call me normal.
Mens' Tears
Fail
Succeed
Womens' Tears
Today's attendance was 52,000.
Now that I think about it, there's no way there could be leap people.
They're just padding the numbers.
A leap
page
occurred
here
A leap
page
occurred
here
We'd planned on five girls, but six came!
A leap gal is fine too.
Anyway, I keep picturing all these little kids playing some game in this big field of rye and all.
Thousands of little kids, and nobody's around - nobody big, I mean - except me.
And I'm standing on the edge of some crazy cliff.
What I have to do, I have
to catch everybody if they
start to go over the cliff
- I mean if they're running
and they don't look where
they're going I have to
come out from somewhere
and catch them.
That's all I do all day. I'd just be the catcher in the rye and all.
I know it's crazy, but that's the only thing I'd really like to be.
Originally published 8th August, Showa 82.
From Chapter 105
The Dropper in the Rye
Find
Your
Doubt in
dubbing
Saga
Yakis-
obunny
Yakisoba
Bread
Pippim @
Lotto
Candy Apples
Takoyaki
Goldfish Scooping
Bait
(potato)
\200
Ice
Gyo-P
Dance CD
Tomioka YakisoIceba
I've caught you, teacher.
Yes, you certainly have caught me.
target shooting
Gundou
Ice
Ice Cream
But how about catch and release?
Catch and release?
Why?
Because, after all, today
-is- Houjoue.
Gundou
target shooting
Ice
Ice Cream
&
Pudding
Houjoue?
It's a Buddhist holiday.
A day where you do good deeds like letting go the fish or animals you catch.
Also, you overlook the failings and mistakes of others.
So today, I'd like you to release me,
One
Play
\634
One
Play
\634
One
Play
\634
and also to overlook what happened with my body double last week!
One
Play
\634
One
Play
\634
One
Play
\634
One
Play
\634
Thank you for releasing me!
Crane
Taiyaki
Tsukimi
Ramune
sweet
dumplings
Tsukimi
Ramune
sweet
dumplings
Let me go
It's Houjoue, isn't it.
Zetsu
Sweets
miyaki
Zetsu
Sweets
miyaki
Sweets
miyaki
Sweets
miyaki
Sweets
miyaki
Sweets
miyaki
Sweets
miyaki
miyaki
miyaki
What's up with your sudden appearance?
miyaki
miyaki
The kindness to let something go through one ear and out the other.
Houjoue isn't just a day, perhaps it's also the lifestyle of Japanese people.
That being “through life”.
That being
Through... life?
I've heard of “slow life”, but...
Through Life
Slow Life
Government Cover
miyaki
No, “through life”.
Ignoring people passed out in the street!
Tetsuya
Keiko
Kei-chan  Snacks
Tetsuya
Ignoring the cries of the neighbors' kids!
Ignoring cruel bullying in the classroom!
Ice Ice  Ice
Ice
Sponge Ca
Shaft
A
Survey
in
Progress
The ability to overlook those is the kindness of the Japanese!
Well, um...
That isn't quite... wait, why am I in all the examples?
Teacher, you've recently decided to try out "through life", haven't you.
No, I haven't!
This is the Rohas family. They're trying "through life", too.
Hi, we're the Rohases.
What?
Oh, nothing.
"Through life", teacher.
The wife is pretty, too.
This is my daughter, Sokotoko.
Through life, through life.
Here, why not have lunch?
Lie
Ignorance is Bliss
I'm terribly sorry, but where is this eel from?
Since it's through food...
Through... food?
Eel is slow food, but if you don't know where it came from it's through food too.
Letting safety, provenance, and toxicity go through one ear and out the other;
that's through food.
I feel there's quite a societal difference between slow food and through food.
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Drugs
No
ba
This is the supermarket we usually go to.
Super Under Through
A
Prefectural
government
lunch
Magic mushrooms
Sugihi-
ratake
It has a great variety of through food.
for hamburgers
as advertised
half-price
Processed foods where you ignore what meat is used.
*** Brand Butter
Dairy products where you ignore their reuse.
Sasani
Super
Cheap
Famous Brand Rice
¥1000
Brand-name rice that's obviously too cheap.
Come on, you shouldn't ignore those!
Hey,
what's up with these veggies!
Produce
Sommelier
advice
Milk
Yubari
Shidou
Why don't you neatly display where they came from!
UFO Cabbage CD
Everyone's Song
UFO Cabbage
Made in China
Apples
Everyone's Song
What's wrong, Kitsu?
Oh, teacher.
Through life?
Butcher
It's a kind lifestyle where you ignore many things.
Didn't we use this same kind of gag a long time ago?
Ignore that too.
Teacher, it looks like you finally get through life!
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Haneka Books
Super Under Through
You mean like what we just did?
Clearance
Tientiensu
It's not that bad. I think I'll try it out.
Drugs
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Ignoring that.
Moved
due to
circum-
stances
Moved
due to
circum-
stances
Pastoral
Definitely ignoring that.
World Baribari Value
Rich Comickers
Ignoring that.
I'm ignoring them all!
If you put it that way, I'm experiencing through life too.
Ohkusa?
Inbox
Hi, this is Yuki. Thanks
for today. Let's hang
out again.
(@'.')@
Reply
Select
Function
Even though I know it, I ignore when my husband's horny.
I don't have the money to go to hospital, so I ignore pains.
I ignore N-bleep-K's demands for money.
If I don't ignore them, I wouldn't be able to go on with my daily life!
I don't know how to put this, but I'm sorry for ignoring things as a hobby.
To be continued
Shall we make you happy?  Find your way to our door
Welcome to our grand reopening
Our clothing clings precariously to our shoulders
For now, forget everyday life
Wipe off the night dew and come in
A still-beating heart?  Blue, and done rare?
It fits well with what you really mean
Poison and lies become our habitual spices
Stick a fork in your unsatisfied sadness
It's fine if you leave what you don't like, just like a child
It'll cheer you up, make you feel better bite by bite
I wave and smile, saying "see you next week"
One-night-only cash
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual paradises
on Earth, interesting comics called
Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei, Blue Man, or
Hata Kenjiro and his assistant who came
to ADR, chipped in their voices, and got
photographed with two of the actresses
is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou  Sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Nozomu
Meru
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
It's Nozomu
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Chiwa Saito
Yajima Akiko
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:
Tamaru Hiroshi
Let's despair over the next volume too!
I've never been invited to a birthday party