The story until now.
Nozomu, who loves peace and Stalin, is a veterinarian practicing exclusively on carrier pigeons.
One day, deciding to become a messenger to take the place of a pigeon that was wounded and could not fly,
he flies (sprints) to the the destination, Higashi-Jujo,
but the yuppie-type Dancer of Darkness at the destination, after they exchange dances, refuses to accept the message.
Somehow, "if you do ten kumbhakas underwater, I'll accept it" sounds like something from a cult.
Rejecting that as a little too much, next, a ten-question quiz was insisted upon.
"Say 'I'll undergo sadhana' ten times" sounds pretty cultish, too.
Hastily, he flees, and says to his taxi driver,
"The Daisakkai is just a ripoff of the Tenchusatsu!  Just a ripoff!"
Feeling the embarassment of seeking agreement, he was rear-ended by a glossy black Century.
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
Towem
Records
・Ken・N Drugs
Faraway Forest
Mother's Cooking
Christmas
Towem Records
En-ya
Snack Shop En-ya
They put a big Christmas tree up in the shopping district this year too.
Shinko Books
All right, light the tree!
Roger!
Huh?  There's no switch.
Futons
It's better if you don't flip the switch.
Boiled Egg Club
Weekly Everyday
Chan
Show up late
Tell a lie
Take a photo
Check him out
Hire another hitman
Stand behind him
Originally published 10th December, Showa 83.
From Chapter 163
The Tragedy of
Do Not Enter
The hell are you talking about?
Isn't having to flip a switch in the midst of the holiday rush troublesome?
Cafe Emotion
There's cords extending from the tree!
If I follow them, I'll find the switch!
Looks like they're under here.
SHAFT
Press
Electric Chair
I wonder which one is the switch for the tree?
Don't flip it!
Dog & Cat
Only Shop
Kotsuma
Pet
8 out of 10 dogs
Prefer it
Shoten-machi branch
This kitty's got its tail up.  Wonder if it's angry?
Wrong.
It's happy!
kittieswiththeirtailsuparehappyeventhough
somanypeoplethinkthey'reangry
it'sjustshowingyouthatitwantstobepetted
It's like a switch flipped in her!
Gifts
I told you not to flip it.
You don't know if it'll flip a switch in someone somewhere.
When you talk to Kobushi about tails, she sure flips a switch.
She sure does.
It's hard to tell what'll flip someone's switch if they hear it.
Some people flip a switch if you talk to them about Mishima Yukio.
This is pretty interesting.
Mishima is—!
Other people, when they get their tax bill.
The bureaucrats are just gonna waste it!  They're picking our bones!
Others when they have a chance to proselytize.
There is no God!
There is.
People who seem mature change completely if their switch is flipped.
It's scary.
I see.
If you talked to Ishida Jun'ichi about socks, that'd flip his switch, wouldn't it.
Jun'ichi's Christmas!
Jun'ichi had no stockings,
so he didn't get any presents.
Ishida's Mer
ry Christmas
So he wrote a letter to Santa wishing for stockings.
Ishida's Mer
stmas
Dear Santa
But he had no stocking to put his new stockings in, so he received none.
tl;dw
Dear Santa
Even now, as an adult, Jun'ichi wears no socks.
Jun'ichi said "Don't need 'em."
"After all, I'm your Santa."
I flipped his switch!
And it even looks like that story flipped the switches of the people listening!
What's up, bro?
Masa.  Let's turn over a new leaf.
This is the end of causing trouble for society.
Bro!
The story we just heard flipped a switch in my heart!
Speak
You flipped another one?
Oh no!  Today, I'm the kind of person that flips everyone's switch!
Golden GinzaShopping District
Year End
Party
\1000 Haircuts
Japanese Mother's Cooking
raoke
Oh my, it's Meru!
Umm.  If I talk to her about phones or something, it'll flip her switch.
A
Free
eu
BOX
I'm not gonna make that blunder!
If I push Meru, she makes a funny noise!
Oh man, it's such a cute noise!
You pushed Meru-Meru!
Large
Medium
Small
You flipped another one.
What a strange switch.
She, herself, is someone's switch.
You must not push Otonashi.
But she makes a funny noise!
Shirokin High School
Now, let's show you the next postcard, sent from pen name "" in Tokyo!
That was horrible...
What turned you all green?
He said he wouldn't hit a girl, so he painted me all green instead!
Green suits you.
Don't say it suits me!
Majiru, don't green shorts suit you?
On
They sure do.
They suit you so well!
Green shorts.
This gives me a creepy feeling.
Will you put these on for me?
These green shorts.
Wear them!
Okay...
I flipped another switch!
Ultra light
There's still people whose switches I might flip.  I've gotta be careful.
Me...  Merry Christmas!
A
Enjoy the
classics
Junk
Christmas
Promotion
Merry Christmas...
Merry
Xmas
Merry as the pitcher, and Mas as the catcher...
mas
Happy x Mas!  Last x Mas!  Mas takes them all!
Oh my.
You flipped another one.
But it's just a calculator.
There's a switch in the times sign.
I don't get what flips people's switches anymore!
I really don't know where switches are.
Really.
In the doggy's nose, there's a switch controlling the BoJ's foreign-exchange intervention!
In the '60s sumo's nipples, there's a switch to shoot off the T-bleep-L fireworks!
There's a famous story that the Governor of Tokyo's second button is the Tokyo Government Office's transformation switch!
Um... hello...  Hello?
Aragi's office intercom is the switch to make Mt. Fuji erupt, so it shouldn't be flipped excessively!
Everyone has a switch somewhere!
Maria knows where Teacher's switch is.
Behind his ears!
That's just a sensitive spot!
Itoshiki Nozomu's
Erogenous zone is his
Ears!!
Itoshiki Nozomu's
Erogenous zone is his
Ears!!
Itoshiki Nozomu's
Erogenous zone is his
Ears!!
Itoshiki Nozomu's
Erogenous zone is his
Ears!!
Itoshiki Nozomu's
Erogenous zone is his
Ears!!
Itoshiki Nozomu's
Erogenous zone is his
Ears!!
Itoshiki Nozomu's
Erogenous zone is his
Ears!!
If you flip the switch behind Teacher's ears, he makes a soft noise and starts to collapse from the lap down!
A soft noise...
Kitakaze Dry Goods
I wanna flip it!
Kimono Rental
It's true!
He collapsed, starting from his lap!
You call that a soft noise?
Maybe you flipped the wrong switch?
Strawberry
Daifu
You flipped Teacher's self-destruct switch!
Or was it his weak point...
By the way, if you press Kaga's mole, the government changes!
Mother's Cooking
I'm on as a proxy.  So what?
Protecting the lives of newborns
Setting them up is not illegal
Their use calls for prudence
There is resistance to calling them "post"
It becomes understood as "abandonment"
Never mind that, how about thinking of making parents and society that don't abandon children
Originally published 30th August, Showa 82.
From Chapter 96
I will not return to Japan.
I was unable to be that resolute.
Well, I don't have time to watch two, so...
Which shall I rent?
Letters from Flags
Rental
Iwo Jima of our
Fathers
This one?
Rental
Letters from Flags
New: One Night
Or this one?
tters from Flags
New
Rental
Letters from Flags
Iwo Jima of our
Fathers
New: One Night
Rap love comedy!!
Chekerap!
New: One Night
Thanks, come again!
Promotion!
Signup is fr
Why!  Why did I choose neither, and rent something dicey-looking instead!
Ittetsu Udon
Salon
Color Beauty
What's up, Teacher?
Golden GinzaShopping District
Ittetsu Udon
Salon
Color Beauty
That happens a lot!
People pick something completely different when they're completely confused about which of two things to go for.
Bar
Sonmin
Chichibu Ramen
Ohkusa.
I should get curry.
I should get a burger.
Palace of Prices
Super Cameo
Gyoza Only
Kita-no-Sho
We
have
Nobel
Curry or a burger...
Palace of Prices
Super Cameo
Gyoza Only
Kita-no-Sho
We
have
Nobel
Gyoza Only
Kita-no-Sho
And?
I got yakiudon.
Even though, when I think of it, I didn't really want yakiudon...
I wonder why.
Huh?  Otonashi?
Phone IC Card
Aquarios
Why on earth did you pick that one?
In stock!
AI TV
Gold Saga
Saga
Chichibu Electric
Canned ramen
has declared
independence
Ikkyu's on a quiz show!
The Japanese-American actor born in LA whose proper
name is Kosugi Ken uses _____ Kosugi as a stage name.
Ikkyu
Zeon
Jimin
Zain
Kane
A or C?
The Japanese-American actor born in LA whose proper
name is Kosugi Ken uses _____ Kosugi as a stage name.
Ikkyu
Zeon
Zain
Jimin
Kane
I wonder which one it is.
Is it A?
Is it C?
B.
B, huh?  Zain?
Is that your final answer?
Zain
Too bad.
Kane
All right!
That's great.
It isn't just me.
Why is it?
People, who have decided on one or the other,
have a mentality of selecting something completely different.
Meeting room
We've narrowed this year's Manga Prize down to these two works.
Love La Doll
Aoyagi Gen
Kyuto! Q-ute
Sakura Chirari
It's tough to pick which is better.
It's unusually worrying.
Let's pick this one.
This one?
Kyuto! Q-ute
Sakura Chirari
Love La Doll
Aoyagi Gen
Or this one.
Love La Doll
Aoyagi Gen
Kyuto! Q-ute
Sakura Chirari
Deep Stagnation
Kumeda
Osamu
Deep
Raku
Why'd we pick that one?
I wonder why.
Indecisive over which, in the end, they make a dicey third choice!
They wonder which car to buy, but in the end,
buy a dicey one rather than either of their choices!
Hoya
Harajuku
Wondering whether to rent in crowded Shinjuku or wide-open Hoya, in the end,
they go halfway and get a room in Nishiogi!
Party
Wondering whether to buy a gag gift or a present that will be truly appreciated, in the end,
Umaibou
they get neither, but rather something dicey, as a present!
All right!
All together now!
Pric
We're in despair!
Pri
Price Erosio
Pric
Price Erosion
Picking a third option after trying to decide between two things has left us in despair!
Golden Ginza Shopping
Middle                 Bldg.
ugs
Sweets
The Munch
All right, we've said it.
Let's go home.
Yeah, let's.
Video
Salon
Very Beauty
Your Local Electronics Store Monma Electronics
Dyna
Dead End
You cannot
cut through
Out of
the park
Nakata Travel
Shinko Bakery
ndry
Snack
Shinko Bakery
I wonder where this is.
Nakata Travel
I've lost my way.
Shinko Bakery
Nakata Travel
You all got lost, too?
Oh no.  Teacher, take a look.
Nakata Travel
ndry
You were there?
Yes, always.
Having lost our paths, in the end,
we've come to Choice-3 City.
Choice-3 City!?
This is a question of responsibility!
You led us, as our teacher, off into another prefecture, you failure!
The fault lies on the side of the school!
Isn't that something to worry about after we get back?
Will you accept responsibility, or won't you?
"Yes" or "no"!?
Spit it out!  "YES" or "NO"!
Nes.
The hell does 'nes' mean!?
It's nes!
Neither "yes" nor "no"!
A third choice!
No              Yes
Speaking in Japanese,
rather than "hai" or "iie".
let us say "haie".
This is absolutely not an attempt to muddy the waters.
It damn well does muddy them!
A little bit of making third choices isn't a bad thing..
You again...
Selecting neither is the mark of a kind heart!
Come on!
We've all arrived here because of third choices that we've made!
Hold it.
I don't make third choices!
I keep it to a clean choice between the first two!
Chiri, your name was a third choice.
My name?
Tome
Mirakuru
Your parents were indecisive over whether to name you Mirakuru or Tome, and in the end,
it seems like they chose Chiri.
iri
Chiri
Laundromat
What do you mean, Mirakuru!?
I want to ask your parents.
Laundromat
"Just why did you choose Chiri?"
That's quite enough!
But Chiri, if you don't mind,
I'll call you Mirakuru.
It's fine if you don't!
Why am I wearing these clothes?
Kino?
Signal
Unsure between my A plan or my B plan, in the end,
I made a third choice that was neither!
Signal
But the end result's the same...
Tamura Cle
Dress
shirts
30% off
Why did she pick him?
Bar Pachin
Fujiyoshi.
When deciding which man to love, in the end,
she picked some dicey guy!
Bar
Soba Feeling
Seeking Franchisees
The whims of a maiden's heart...
It's something from a game.
We're fully aware.
Yes, this is Choice-3 City, where third choices gather!
It's a fabulous third choice!
Unsure whether to use Miyazaki
or Takahata, in the end have
the big boss direct
Unsure whether to merge or sell,
in the end start a new team
Unsure whether to pick Japan or
Brazil's team, in the end picking Qatar
Unsure whether to compromise and sign or wait for a better offer, in the end choose promotion
Unsure whether to visit the mountains or
the sea, in the end stay at home
Unable to choose between au and Docomo, in the end,
they chose to send signals into space using trees!
Unable to choose either French or Italian, in the end,
they chose to select Molmol!
Somehow, these third choices are becoming lunatic!
Unable to choose between the left and right brain, in the end,
we chose to listen to the voices!
After all, they're third choices.
Their reasoning is beyond imagination.
Japanese Restaurant Mother's Cooking
They're not just other people's problems!
They're wonderful choices that you, too, will make from now on!
Unable to choose between briefs or boxers, in the end,
instead, you'll try burying the lower half of your body!
Unable to choose between buying a cat or a dog, in the end,
you'll decide you're a bird and try to fly!
Tamayocchi
Unable to choose between having bread or rice, in the end,
you'll make a claymation about Marukawa Tamayo!
Those kind of choices make life!
Nishikawa
Florist
Hajime
Nishikawa
Minami
Fujita Sweets
If I have to show my shame living that kind of life with an unclear meaning,
I'd rather die!
To live, hiding my shame...
Or to choose death, like a man!
Life or death..  In the end, I choose—!
Door for Babies
Itoshiki Hospital
Baby's Cradle
Baby Post
Baby inside.
There's an adult in the Baby Post!
We never assumed there'd be a grown man in there.
You can let me do my life over, right?
We can't.
What shall we do?
Stuff him in the Youkai Post or something.
Heaven
Human
Earth
Outer
Combined
Looks like she's satisfied with it.
Something-or-other High
Why did they choose this?
It isn't like you to have regrets.
What's wrong?
Unable to decide between the two, in the end,
I chose this, something completely different.
Unable to choose between what and what?
Why did I choose this!?
Here goes!
Here's the toss!
Tea House
Lemon Sour
Draft Chuhi
Draft beer
Ramen
Beach hut
Yakisoba
Rental
Para
Tub
Grilled
Millet
\300
Are you lonely, young master Nozomu?
Not at all.
Grilled
Millet
\300
But perhaps it would be better if even one person noticed.
It's because it is, after all, a body double.
Grilled
Millet
\300
But isn't having a body double a bit too grandiose?
We live in a dangerous world.
Even if you say so...
Isn't that taking excessive caution?
No self-confidence
Not really feeling loved, even with a lover
Thinks of their own thoughts as meaningless
Cannot express their opinion
Normally watches people's expressions
Do not act unless ordered
Originally published 1st August, Showa 82.
From Chapter 104
Doctor Kahogo
Even it's not, the world nowadays is full of excessive caution.
Do Not Enter
No photography
Like with tourist attractions you can't approach at all, in order to protect them!
Antibacterial
Or with overdone antibacterial goods!
Withdrawal
limit \100,000
Or bank ATMs limiting withdrawals due to the amount of "hey, remember me?" fraud!
Just how protective will the government's countermeasures against NEETs get!?
I'm in despair!
An overprotective society has left me in despair!
But, big brother, you were reared overprotectively.  That's almost laughable to hear coming from you.
Rin.  I was not raised overprotectively or anything.
That was strictness!
"Fed oblong rice", "Put in an oblong bath", "Given oblong books"
More importantly, brother.
Beach hut Okinojima
Over there, a protective group is opening up.
A protective group!?
Being chewed out by a parent who wouldn't give you lunch money!
You've got a lot of nerve!
Deciding to cast their favor upon the child with the worst grades!
I'll take special care of you!
Getting spanked just for taking a fall playing sports!
No roughhousing!
That kind of protective group!?
It's all over!
The protective ones have ganged up and are gonna lynch me!
Isn't this exactly the kind of thing a body double is there for?
Yes, but...
I missed!?
It's very dangerous over there, too.
Would you rather switch with him?
Right, right.
Beach hut
Grilled
Millet
\300
Takeda Shingen had five body doubles, didn't he.
Big brother.  How chicken of you.
Beach hut
Okinojima
It's better if I join the protective group, isn't it.
Yes, but evet if it's called the "protective group", those who take it a little too far are gathered there.
It's an overprotective group.
An overprotective group?
Well... Protectors tend to be overprotective, don't they.
Curry
Yakisoba
Oyakodon
Tondon
China Don
Gyudon
Shaved
ice menu
Berry  Milk  Lemonade
Pineapple  Dream  Mint
Peach  Coconut  Aqua
You don't look like a protector.
No, Kotonon is very overprotective of her skin.
Blog  Photo   Diary
Sunburn is a net
idol's worst enemy
You certainly are.
You're someone who's amazingly overprotective against sunburn.
You may as well not come to the beach.
So you mean this is a collection of such overbearing protectors?
Well, it is an overprotective group.
What are you overprotective of?
Comics.
This is my copy to save.
Combat Butler Hayachi
Other than this, I have one to read and one to lend out.
After this, if LEs or ones with pack-ins come out, I'll buy three each of those as well.
Monjayaki
Bread
Curry bun
Cheese bun
That's certainly overprotective, isn't it.
Aren't the contents the same?
There's no reason to go along with unsavory sales practices.
Brother, if you say that now, you won't be able to perform unsavory sales practices.
Goku Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei
LE on sale  2008/10/17
Goku Sayonara,
Zetsubou-sensei
LE on sale
2009/2/17
If I were, perhaps, to ever write a book,
I would be happier if the reader treasured their one copy forever.
Still thinking you're the only one favored by God...
If it sells...
Just maybe, if it sells...
Zan Sayonara,
Zetsubou-sensei
DVD vol. 1 on
sale sometime
in 2009
By the way, brother, This belongs to Fujiyoshi, one of your students.
Commencing armed intervention to
end all warfare with Gundam
She cut it out of a magazine and laminated it.
That's overprotective too, isn't it.
About what you just said, with the "that too".
There's a song registered with exactly the same lyrics.
Pay up for the reproduction rights to the music.
Licensing fee
To be continued
Shall we make you happy?  Find your way to our door
Welcome to our grand reopening
Our clothing clings precariously to our shoulders
For now, forget everyday life
Wipe off the night dew and come in
A still-beating heart?  Blue, and done rare?
It fits well with what you really mean
Poison and lies become our habitual spices
Stick a fork in your unsatisfied sadness
It's fine if you leave what you don't like, just like a child
It'll cheer you up, make you feel better bite by bite
I wave and smile, saying "see you next week"
One-night-only cash
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Ishida Jun'ichi,
Minomonta, or monster parent is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou  Sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Matching the song, let's draw dandily, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Zetsubou
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Nakamura Yuichi
Mugihito
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:
Nakamura Asumiko
Let's despair over the next volume too!