The story until now.
Even though the new government sent him to Holland in Europe to study tactics,
their prevailing strategy was American-style shock and awe.
Awaiting him was the expensive euro, making the base subway fare ¥1,000.
Though he relied on the Japanese government's PR comics there,
the enviable starting enviable salary for a novice French comicker was 90 euros a page.
"That's more than you'd make after ten years at a major company!  You should thank the stars of the Seine!"
Thinking such, Nozomu, holed up in Paris, sunk into depression, and searching for salvation, turned to the world of fantasy science.
Amid the citizenry, he argued in Esperanto that the use of lamps would ruin the country,
and his selfmade steamboat, the Himiko, burned in the Seine.
Turning his shame into springs, he gained notoriety among the nobility of London as the "Spring Man".
"Western powers, tremble before me!  My science will protect Asia!",
he declared, setting his sights on a UFO base in Pagotania.
At that point, he received a telegram from his fatherland saying "Come home and marry Miyazaki Aoi."
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
Shocked that there were still no storyboards on editing day
Shocked that the art wasn't done by ADR day
Shocked that dubbing got pushed back a week
Shocked that some cuts weren't done on delivery day
Shocked that we finished the video on broadcast day
Shocked that it actually broadcast at the normal time
Originally published 17th September, Showa 83.
From Chapter 152
Yeah, it's a surprise,
I muttered hollowly
Can we meet up after class?
What do I do!? My heart isn't ready!
It's about the poster for the upcoming Reading Week.
Should it be green on a white background, or white on a green background?
Well, um.  What are you talking about?
Reading                       Week
Fall is for Reading
I told you I wanted to talk to you about something, right?
Aren't you planning to go to an art college?
When you're called out somewhere and you're sure someone's going to declare their love,
but nothing happens, that's a surprise!
Leave SHAFT's
radio to me!
Composition T
The Japanese, who are deeply suspicious, tend to be more surprised when, in fact, nothing happens.
Leave SHAFT's
radio to me!
Composition T
Leave SHAFT's
radio to me!
Composition T
Leave SHAFT's
radio to me!
Composition T
Leave SHAFT's
radio to me!
Composition T
Leave SHAFT's
radio to me!
Composition T
Leave SHAFT's
radio to me!
Composition T
As a result of things which don't happen, they are reverse surprised!
To illustrate, say that, on your birthday, you receive a phone call
Birthday
Today
Hello
We're all going drinking, c'mon!
from a friend.  You show up nonchalantly expecting to be celebrated.
Thanks!
He's here, he's here!
yay
You drink normally,
We're splitting the tab, your share's \3000.
and say goodbye normally without anything happening.  That feeling.
Laters.
To me.  To me.
That kind of reverse surprise!
That's miserable.
Yeah, that definitely happens.
Oh, Miss Chie.
Just before elections, you get a phone call from a classmate
who you haven't seen in years and were never that close with.
You just talk normally about the old days, and then hang up.
Nothing happening is more of a surprise.
Yeah, that's definitely shocking.
Man, I'm hot.
Fake Anime Goods
Copyright
Yayoi
Vanishing
Kino
A
Let's hurry up and change.
A plain white T-shirt!
A
Fake Anime Goods
Copyright
There being nothing there is more surprising!
In this modern era where everything goes too far,
our destination is the point of no surprise!
It's
me
When you get a call going "it's me, it's me!",
It's
me
it's more of a surprise when, rather than a scam, it really is your grandson!
It's
me
The End
Recently, at concerts, it's more of a surprise when there isn't an encore!
When the Chuo line runs on time with no incidents, that's more of a surprise!
It's more surprising when things don't happen!
It's the feeling you get when watching a horror film, thinking "it's coming, it's coming",
I'm just imagining things.
but you end up being more surprised that nothing happens, right?
Hey, Teacher.
Wanna come up and listen to a song?
Sure, why not?
Dug-Out
Apartments
Teacher's doing something serious!
Thanks, please come again.
Dug-Out
Teacher, did anything happen?
No, nothing at all.
Nothing having happened is more surprising!
Hey, Sekiutsu.
Japanese don't understand.
How surprising the everyday peace in this country is.
You're right.
What's up with that ending!?
Happy Birthday Abiru
You remembered.  They completely ignored it at school.
Sorry for the reverse surprise.
But it's okay.
Are you happy now?
All the players have, all across the country, started their training season!
Is it already that time?
Training, huh.
It's about time for us to start.
I don't really have my licence
My hobby is collecting cicada shells
My scalp is-
I hit level 99
I can't do it
I'm sorry
Originally published 7th January, Showa 84.
From Chapter 165
Confession Crepe Team
Teacher is standing in front of the police box as if he's brooding over something!
I did it.
Teacher, just what did you do!?
Year-End
Special Watch
Nothing.
But you just—!
No, that's...
Confession training!
It's confession training.
Why do you have to train for that sort of thing!?
It's difficult to admit one's own mistakes.
When that time comes, will you be able to confess?
Goro Memb
Insider
A
There are many circumstances in which,
K-on!
First-ever #1!
A
Doubtful Detective T
Next April
if you apologize for a crime the moment it's committed, it'll be over without becoming a big deal!
Have you seen
this man
Modern Japanese, unable to admit their faults, require such training!
Have you seen
this man
Itoshiki Me
So, just what did you do?
Have you seen
this man
Metsu
Koishikawa
1-chome
Police Box
I said, it's just confession training.
Metsu
What are you saying!?
Teacher!
If you're doing confession training, you've got to assume you've done a particular crime.
It's image training!
An image of my crimes?
Biting a dog's ear
Sleep-talking Note
Writing down what people say in their sleep
Have you seen
this man
Itoshiki Metsu
I did it.
You can't think of anything major, can you.
Koishikawa
Have you seen
this man
Metsu
Can you really call that confession training!?
If you can't do it,
can't you just
apologize and
it'll be fine?
Fujii
I want greater crimes!  Ones that you regret from the bottom of your heart!
I...
I did it!
This is the first time I've seen such sublime confession!
I wonder just what grand crime she's envisioning!
A
Odani High School
If you go for it when you still haven't warmed up...
Anyway, I'd like you all to make it through simultaneous confession training without any injuries.
All right, you're all guilt-ridden.
I'd like you all to visualize your crimes.
Rabbit
house
Socks
Trash
Lehman
Your envisioned crimes are all over the place!  This will never work for synchronized confession.
Everyone needs to get on the same page.
moto
mura
ACA
Tatsuwa
If you put it that way,
we've got to do -that-.
Friend
Friend     ship
ship
Friend
Friend     ship
I did it.
I used up the life insurance.
I lured him to Minato, then took the glasses off.
I strangled with bandages.
I looted a corpse and brought the clothing to a pawnshop.
I split the earth.
Just what kind of crimes against whom are you envisioning!?
Well, there's plenty of cases in which
synchronized confession would be better, but...
Hey.
Friendship
Nishimatsu
Who's
contributing
One person says something different, and the story changes back and forth.
If the story is inconsistent, it just throws more fuel on the fire.
There's a standard for everyone having
what they're apologizing for straight and all together.
Call this the "confession mark".
You just wanted to say that!
Advance
Twist
Isn't it naïve to lessen crimes just because they've been confessed to?
If anything, it can be more annoying!
Mammoth
Urepi
Friendship
Manifesto
Oshi
A
We're admitting to it!
We're going out!
How annoying!
Sry!
That's not a crime.
Though it may be capital.
Even if it isn't a crime, coming out with a secret can be thought of as confession.
Huh?  Dad?
I'm confessing.
I'm confessing!
My newspaper is—
I'm shocked!
Yes...  It seems training in being confessed to is also required.
Those who suddenly hear a confession may do something dangerous, too!
Confessing to an affair.
Confessing one's tastes.
Sorry, I've gotta go.
Having someone admit to not being a virgin.
You conceited-!
If you don't dissolve for four
years, you'll be overpowering.
Let them do it
once thinking we'd
punish them, and
it became a problem.
Zimbabwe
For both those who do it and those who it is done to, confession training is important.
An even less possible dream.
A letter on an arrow!
It says that confession training is forbidden!
If this permeates out, the whole world of comics will be at risk of destruction!
Why!?
Everyone.
The perpetrator is among us.
It's me.
I did it!
Fin
So the story doesn't hold together...
If confession training continues to spread,
our precious Conan and Kindaichi will be able to solve things without getting their hands dirty, right?
We must continue training in order to take a load off the VIPs!
I may have said it,
but confession training will make all sorts of comics and films fall apart!
Let's start the first confession gymnastics!
It's already captured the hearts of the general public!
Just who is Ki—
Dea***te
I did it.
I'm confessing! This is the real me.
The world of comics has taken catastrophic damage from confession training!
It's not just the world of comics!
80% of Manufacturers
It's bad for all of Japanese society!
Nine-tenths of politicians have capitulated to corruption investigations, and the Diet has completely stopped!
Eight-tenths of manufacturers have admitted that their products are defective!
Treating their failure seriously with a recall!
The producer himself acknowledged how dull his projects are, and voluntarily stopping releasing film after film!
Everyone is confessing too much!  Japan is grinding to a halt!
Now, you should confess too!  Confess!
I shall never confess!
I'll run until the statute of limitations lapses!
Fun      Fun      Fun
Itoshiki Family Grave
It's becoming more moving
Fifty Years Later
Ito
It's been a while, teacher.
I can say this since the statute of limitations has lapsed.  I...
Teacher, I...
Grandma Kaere, whose grave is this?
No one's in particular.
ve
What a touching story.
What's with this dramaticism?
Hito
Common
It's Granny Normal.
She's drinking kelp tea.
Like normal.
Let's go!
Yeah!
Don't call me normal!
A mystery train,
with an unknown destination.
Will that law pass
Will there be a stay of execution
Is it better to have paid into one's pension
Is it better to have bought a bike than to ride the trains and busses
Will there be a fourth season
Does anyone read these subtitles
Originally published 27th December, Showa 82.
From Chapter 179
The Last, and the First Enoden
That's just to trick kids.
There's no such thing as an unknown destination, is there?
It fits in with the schedules of other trains,
so its destination is set from the beginning.
This world is full of things like that.
Excuse me, but you seem to be a teacher.
Survey about education
Thoughts on the
state of education
Can I get you to answer this survey?
Survey about education
Thoughts on the
state of education
Survey about education
Thoughts on the
state of education
Survey about education
Thoughts on the
state of education
Survey about education
Thoughts on the
state of education
Survey about education
Thoughts on the
state of education
Survey about education
Thoughts on the
state of education
Is education dead?
I don't think so, but I don't really know.
Don't you have something to say about it?
There's nothing there.
I see, so it is.  Then what do you think the problem is with modern education?
"Education is dead."
Don't you just want me to say that?
Haven't you already made up your mind?
Lately, there's been many cases of questions asked with a predetermined answer.
Conquer
Ill-omened
day
Nationwide
Sit-In
Tactics
Peace
Are Hentai Games Contributing to
the Dropping Birthrate?
Is your son okay?
A rapid increase
in youth who can love
only 2D!
Melting the minds
of youth
Crushing their
humanity
A fearsome devil!
Arrested on the *th
The suspect, *** Rabbit, also uses daily!
Hiring
Immediately
Producer
5th Sanosuke
Leading questions, designed to reach one's conclusion, looking for not an opinion, only agreement...
Questions where you just want a particular answer.  Yes, just like this mystery train with its destination already fixed...
There are people who ask
questions after they've decided
We fight every day now.
Should I break up with my boyfriend?
Break up with him?
If you don't like him, then shouldn't you?
Well, he's not really all that bad.  And...
Haven't you already come to a conclusion?
In terms of love, there really are people who ask even after they've made up their mind.
Hi, I'd like to buy a TV,
but I'm not sure if I want a plasma or an LCD.
Plasma Digital OTA
As Advertised
int Deception
EGO Point
Year-end Special
\10,000
I see.  This plasma TV, currently our sale of the week, may be to your interest.
The apple
has been se
I repeat
ppl has
been sent
But don't plasmas use a lot of power?
Analog
They did.  Nowadays, they're about average.
And won't it heat up my room?  Also, I'm worried about it making a high-pitched noise.
It looks like he's already made up his mind.
Mangain Kurayaminosuke
Beat Ne**ma!
I think maybe I should quit drawing it.
Yes.  If you quit...
No, wait.  If I do, I haven't the foggiest what I'll draw next.
And I have no talents other than drawing comics, so it'll be tough to find a job at my age.
Looks like he's already made up his mind.
Mangain Kurayaminosuke
Beat Ne**ma!
He looks so bitter.
Oh, chief editor!
Can you keep up with serialization?
Yeah, I'll keep trying a little bit longer.
I see.  But sometimes it's best to quit when you're ahead.
It's unlucky to lose freshness, both in writing and in reading.
And it looks like he's already made up his mind, too.
That's a bit too realistic.
I wonder if I should stop watching this anime.
Shouldn't you?  It's pretty dull.
Well, there's an interesting episode every once in a while.  If I don't watch, I'll feel like I've missed it.
Pantyshot
I love maidens
I, Too, Am Gun***
You've already made up your mind!
Un
ending
Buy a Guitar
To not accept any answer but the one you seek...
The world has become a little bit more disgusting.
Perhaps it's better to die.
If you want to die...
If you want to die, then give it a shot!
But my heart's not ready!
Wait, this is dangerous!
What if I had died!?
Looks like you've already made up your mind.
I've come to understand that you have a voracious appetite for life, teacher.
Wrong!
It's not that I want to live, it's that I most assuredly won't die!
Disembarking?
Endless
The Aruaru
Fictional
Crazy Train
This is a gigantic terminal.
From here, mystery trains bound to many different destinations depart.
Get on, everyone!  With your opinions and actions, the destinations change!
Even if they say that train's destination is unknown, where it's going has been determined from the start.
To (prove that the kids in) Shibuya (are running wild)
It's for those who believe the youth of Shibuya are running wild, and set up TV interviews expressly for that opinion!
Night Train to Soichiro
That night train's destination is determined.
No matter which arguments you make, its destination has to be Tahara Shoichiro's opinion: the Asanama Train!
Night Train to Soichiro
The Culprit is Ya
Gathering information nearby based on the conclusion that he's the culprit!
Not looking for a relationship
When they can't risk being discriminatory, they screen employees with tests.
Mystery trains with their predetermined destinations have left me in despair!
Everyone wants to get on the train leading to their preconceived conclusion.
No, they ride them even if they shouldn't!
So you aren't gonna pay me back?
What do we do now, huh?
Well?  What do we do now?
Where's that train going?
After this it goes underground and becomes a subway.
Then it reaches an underground station.
Even if we know its destination, it still becomes lost.
In this world, there are station names that aren't shown even if we know the destination!
Excuse me, from which terminal does the train to Paradise on Earth depart?
It used to depart from the furthest-left terminal,
but it's had so few passengers lately that it's been cancelled.
It used to be packed full of students.  Who had all already made up their minds the same way...
...So, what do we do from here?
Teacher, how about finally deciding on a woman?
Hmm, that's right.
With whom should I—?
Haven't you already made up your mind?
...Yes.
This is an express train that only those who've made up their minds on weighty decisions can ride.
NEETs who've decided what to do next.
Politicians who've made difficult decisions about the nation's future.
Well, we've arrived.
The terminal station— The terminal station—
Putting it Off—  Arriving at Putting it Off—
I've decided to put it off.
That's not a decision!
Congratulaitons, everyone!   You've made a decision!
We've decided to think about it in two or three years!
I've decided to borrow from the next generation.
To be honest, this is the most popular and well-used station.
I've decided to put off losing my virginity.
I've decided to put off contributing to my pension fund.
I've decided to put off seeing a doctor.
Tapering Off
Cancellation   Self-Protection
Sales      Popularity
Tapering Off
Cancellation   Self-Protection
Sales      Popularity
Tapering Off
Cancellation   Self-Protection
Sales      Popularity
Tapering Off
Cancellation   Self-Protection
Sales      Popularity
Tapering Off
Cancellation   Self-Protection
Sales      Popularity
Tapering Off
Cancellation   Self-Protection
Sales      Popularity
It always happens after volume ten. No matter what you do.
Shall we make you happy?  Find your way to our door
Welcome to our grand reopening
Our clothing clings precariously to our shoulders
For now, forget everyday life
Wipe off the night dew and come in
A still-beating heart?  Blue, and done rare?
It fits well with what you really mean
Poison and lies become our habitual spices
Stick a fork in your unsatisfied sadness
It's fine if you leave what you don't like, just like a child
fuka
P.N.
Fuura Kafuka
Neighbor
It'll cheer you up, make you feel better bite by bite
I wave and smile, saying "see you next week"
One-night-only cash
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Lehman Brothers, JIS Mark, or The Asia is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou-sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Matching the song, let's draw together, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Terashima Takuma
Goto Saori
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:
Asada Hiroyuki
How there have been times—
Times of brown despair
Yuaahhhn Yuyohhhn
Yuyayuyon
Let's despair over the next volume too!