The story until now.
Nozomu is imprisoned within Shibusawa Manor as the spy who stole the camp's dirty book.
The Count enters during his interrogation as he's being struck with a Gewalt stick
and told “Spit it out, Nyaho Nyaho-Tamakloe!” (a code name he doesn't remember).
He was told “You're a natural Homo Ludens”, fitted with a mysterious toy, the likes of which he had never seen, and set free.
Shaking off the Count's loud laughing “it's a toy for the sake of toys”, he seeks shelter at a private house.
But an old man resembling Shirasu Jiro scolds him saying “You have no principles”
and trains him in the construction of Northern European furniture.
At that time, the bullet of an assassin from GHQ strikes a passerby girl—
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
It's finally Sunday.
Showa 83
Sunday
I put on my brand-new white sneakers.
All right, let's go out!
Originally published 4th June, Showa 83.
From Chapter 141
How I Became a Real Human
If you don't mind TPO, that's what'll happen.
If you go out in the rain wearing white sneakers.
But—!
A convertible in June!?
Come on, mind TPO!
Warnings for convertibles:
Spring
Summer
Autumn
Winter
Pollen
Direct Sunlight
Typhoons
Snowfall
The world is full of things like that! It really irritates me!
Like carrying golf clubs while getting questioned due to suspicion of being bribed with golfing trips!
Stoppage time
1 minute
Or getting a red card during stoppage time!
Or the current Rambo's front line!
Come on, mind TPO!
So...
June brides aren't minding TPO, are they.
Huh? Why?
Having a ceremony in the rainy season?
It's likely to put both the celebrators and the celebrated on a poor footing!
The rice shower for luck becomes a rice soup!
The bouquet the bride tosses seems like the kind of artificial flower that blooms when put in water!
There are many couples who plan on marrying in the coming month of June,
so I don't think saying “June brides aren't minding TPO” is minding TPO.
Well, I guess that's true.
But after all, they're June brides. Getting married in June can't be bad timing.
That's the point.
I'm not too familiar with it,
but isn't that just something that the industry distorted because business is so slow during the rainy season?
June bride: Since Jupiter's wife Juno watches over married life, brides who have their wedding in June are called “June Brides.”
It's like the TPO Hiraga Gennai came up with for the Midsummer Day of the Ox.
If you eat eel on the Day of the Ox, it'll sit poorly in your stomach.
Peak time for soba is 11/12
After that, if you go to refresh yourself by getting soba,
you'll feel like it's a bad time for soba and not want to go back!
You've tried to mind TPO, but in reverse, you ended up not minding it!
Even when going to the bike shop to buy a bike, you can be treated like you're not minding TPO.
What do you mean?
Sports
Specialty
Shop
Sports
Specialty
Shop
Hello, I'd like to buy a moped.
Tour de France
documentary
A moped?
Limited production run!!
About Us
Sports
Specialty
Shop
We don't normally sell those here.
You probably
should've gone
to Daiei
Limited production run!!
About Us
Sports
Specialty
Shop
I guess we can order one for you...
No, that's fine.
Even though I went to a bike shop to buy a bike, I was treated like I wasn't minding my TPO!
What can cause one to completely miss TPO when they're trying to mind it is a mystery!
And now, the news.
New model
The fire that began before dawn today is still burning. Firefighters are still active on the scene.
This BGM on the news...
It's the theme from Backdraft.
New model
They wanted to keep TPO in mind when selecting music,
but instead, they chose something imprudent!
I wonder if they'll get complaints.
Oh my, where are you going all decked out like that?
To a party at a high-class hotel.
Going to a party at a hotel in formal wear is minding your TPO.
Admiral Hotel
Formal wear, huh.
If you go in formal wear to a party where comickers are gathered, you may think you're minding TPO.
But instead, the result is that you aren't!
The world is full of things like that!
On the other hand, going to an anime launch party, everyone around me was dressed in formal wear and I was the only one who came casual.
Showing up with a present on Christmas Eve,
only to be told to mind the TPO and come back on the 26th!
You broadcast a show in an unstable dictatorship, thinking it'll be fine because it's just a cartoon about robots.
Machine Voltes V
But you end up not minding the TPO when the final episode is about a revolution!
BROADCAST
CANCELED
Situations where you try to mind it but it comes out the other way!
Sayonara,
Zetsubou-sensei
Kumeta Koji
This comic is the same.
Even if we try to be prudent and mind TPO with our gags,
After submitting manuscript
Meat nunchaku smackdown
that kind of incident happens after printing,
Delivery
Magazine
and by the day it goes on sale, the gags don't mind TPO!
What an
imprudent
gag!
Sunbay
Zump
Flass
If we try to mind future TPO...
We won't be able to use anything besides this type of impossible gag!
A Morlock
destroys
Sho****kan
※(It may possibly also have been an alien)
Oh my.
Not minding TPO certainly makes things dramatic.
For example, take a 9th-grader about to take his exams...
And send in a sexy tutor.
All right, answer the next question.
Calling the radius of the circle
forming the base of the cone r, the
length of the generatrix L, and its
height h, calculate the volume of
the cone... πr ×h÷3  L=14, r=5
h can be derived from the
Pythagorean theorem; for a right
triangle with sides a, b, and the
hypotenuse c, c²=a²+b²
Thus, h²=14²-5²=169 h=13
thus, 52π×13×13=325
Question
Find me the volume of this cone.
I can't, teacher!
I can't form an image just from looking at it on paper!
If I don't see it as a physical, 3D object—!
Cones!
These aren't cones!
Their height!
Let me measure their height!
Oh no!
The radius is &($% cm...
Oh no...
Calling the radius of the circle
forming the base of the cone r, the
length of the generatrix L, and its
height h, calculate the volume of
the cone... πr ×h+3  L=14, r=5
Oh no!
Oh no! I can't study without my eraser!
Excuse me!
That's not an eraser!
Naughty!
Ms. Kaere
A
To Be Continued
This time from behind!
Sending a sexy tutor to a middle-school kid about to take his exams certainly isn't minding TPO!
But isn't it exciting?
Certainly. It seems like it'd be a popular basis for a story.
31 female students
Adventuring on a pirate ship
12 little sisters
A beautiful woman comes out of the TV
Love scenes on the battlefield!
It isn't the time for that kind of thing, but it's still exciting!
Rather than a murder in a disorderly city,
incidents in the peaceful countryside grab people's attention!
Deadline O/X
Rather than games you play in your free time,
games you play right before deadline are more fun!
Deadline O/X
That's right. Not minding TPO is more interesting.
You were there?
Always.
The scene in that hit movie where the heroines met was dramatic because they didn't mind TPO.
phone
cigarette
(NB): While on a bullet train
Well, it was a hit.
I disagree.
Teacher, if you don't mind your TPO, you'll sell.
Sell?
Hidamari
High
But how?
I was brought up well, so I'm always minding myself.
There's a fast way to not mind TPO!
Don't eat bleepJoy during the Sengoku period!
Don't play Witch bleeping during the Sengoku period!
It's simple with just a time slip!
Now you're not minding TPO!
That's certainly true, but that's because it's a different era!
Don't text people during the Sengoku period!
Don't be a shut-in during the Sengoku period!
Don't read doujinshi during the Sengoku period!
Mitsuhide x
Nobunaga
But there's one person who fits right in.
I shall rule this country!
She certainly matches the era,
but the art style doesn't match at all.
We must keep TPO in mind while drawing.
Right, right.
Summer is
Rental Boats
and Floats
It's the sea!
Showa 83
Monday
Sea
Day
It's Sea Day
The delivery of
this episode,
due to Happy Monday,
was a great blow
to the staff
(2009/7/17)
Not particularly bitter about it or anything
Originally published 9th July, Showa 83.
From Chapter 145
Celebrated Pedigree
Sea Day... A Japanese holiday.
Shaved Ice
Strawberry Melon Blue Hawaii
A festive day.
Can people from landlocked prefectures celebrate it?
Shaved Ice
Strawberry Melo
Strawberry Melon Blue Hawaii
Mita Takoyaki
Er?
I asked, can people from landlocked prefectures celebrate it?
“As Japan is an oceanic nation, Sea Day is a celebration for all its people.”
Isn't that how it is?
That seems rather... indelicate.
Map of Japan
Saitama, Tochigi, Gunma, Yamanashi, Nagano, Gifu, Nara!
There are seven landlocked prefectures!
Everyman
Coming out
Shaved Ice
It's unfair to make these landlockeders celebrate Sea Day!
You've been making up a lot of words lately, teacher.
It's like buying a kid a game when he doesn't have the system to play it on!
Or, if the whole country really does have to celebrate,
why don't we make them take it all the way? Even if it's overdoing it!
Like this!
Dumping
shrimp chips
in the bathtub
so it smells
like the sea
Painting your back
blue so it seems
like you're underwater
blue
Affixing Apollo
chocolates to your knees
to feel like you're growing
barnacles
Don't just go and say that!
The Happy
Monday rule
A rule whereby certain national
holidays of Japan are moved to Monday
And beyond that, Sea Day makes it a “Happy Monday”!
But who's happy!?
Because of it, deadlines get moved up a day!
holiday
Happy Monday
Just how much do you think that makes comickers suffer!
Er, I mean, just how much do you think that makes the self-employed suffer!
Deadline moved up
Aren't public servants the only ones who're “happy” about it!?
Teacher, you're a public servant.
It's a holiday we can't celebrate!
There's so many like that.
Certainly, in this world,
there are so many things we can't
honestly celebrate even if we wanted to.
The owner of the funeral home near my house said so...
Fukui Funerals
Thanks to
you for 30
years and
3000 ceremonies
Thanks to
you for 30
years and
3000 ceremonies
Fukui Funerals
This is our 30th year in business,
but from the customers' standpoint, we can't celebrate.
Coincidentally, we just avoided celebrating our 3000th client.
Well, ummm.
Movie about the embalmer
Got the Academy Award
He's right about that.
I was going to congratulate a girl from my neighbourhood,
but she doesn't know who the father is.
I don't know whether to celebrate it or not...
A new life should be celebrated unconditionally.
ce
My dad won a contest,
National Hair Growth Grand Prix
Sponsored by Regrowth 55
but I don't know whether it's good or bad to celebrate!
Harumi is finally getting her debut in a magazine, but...
Isn't that something to celebrate?
But it's a collaboration, so...
Why is she working on -that-!?
I don't know whether I should celebrate or not.
Make up your mind!
But there's no reason for it!
Of course it's unclear whether it's good or bad to debut on a project with so little anticipation.
Leadership Clinic
It'd be far better to have been asked to draw something like Deableep Note.
You were there?
Always.
Big brother, it's her first victory!
My favorite horse had her first victory!
Isn't that a happy occasion?
And she was so popular after 300 straight losses...
I wanted to show you the audience's dry spell, brother.
It certainly was a dry spell.
Yes. The modern world...
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
Is full of things that can't be celebrated even if you wanted to!
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
• One's second child (in China)
• Clarisse's wedding
• Attendance award for radio gymnastics
• Recent invitation to a gourmet tour of China
• Going to an amusement park with
a bro, getting picked for the *0,000th
visitor ceremony
• Two-rank promotion, effective immediately
• Promotion to a rural branch
• Obama City, ignored by Mr. Obama
over \180
Oil
Wheat
High-priced
Disgusting news !
Nowadays, the inflation and rising oil prices are bringing about a new mood: Self-deprivation.
Nowadays, vacation days...
Privation
...are becoming privation days!
days
Shaved Ice
Strawberry Melo
Not vacation?
Vacation days
Privation days
Privation.
Celebrate
Sea Day
Sea
Vacation is limited to the small segment of the population with spare time and money.
The vast majority spend their leisure time in self-deprivation,
staying near home, doing sober, subdued things—privation!
Like suspension from school.
It's like house arrest, so I can't say you're wrong.
Vacation day
Privation day
There's no longer celebration in Japan, only deprivation!
This deprivatory mood spreads throughout the world.
Cucumber
Behold!
Even if he works, he won't be rewarded, so he deprives himself of employment!
Cucumber
Fail! Employment!
Employment
Fail
Cucumber
Employment
Fail
Cucumber
He can't afford to get married on his low salary!
Fail! Wedding!
Wedding
Fail
He already doesn't have enough money to pay his tuition!
Fail! On getting accepted!
Getting
accepted!
Fail
Getting
accepted!
Fail
A TV anime was too luxurious, so it was self-deprived to an OAD.
Fail! Anime adaption!
Anime adaption
Fail
Do Not Enter
Safety   First
Road construction in this era of tight finances!
Fail! Opening!
Opening!
Fail
Ministry of ****, Infrastructure, Transport, and Tourism   Transport Bureau
...But I guess those are always still “Hail! Opening!”
Hail
Opening
Those, of all things, should learn some self-deprivation!
Privation's pr...
That's like the pur in purge, right?
It's like the pur in purge, isn't it.
Didn't see that, didn't see that.
Very well, how does everyone think we should spend privation days?
How shall we spend privation days?
I know plenty of dull ways to spend days off.
Should you be out here?
Huh?
It's a privation day, so you shouldn't try to enjoy yourself like on a vacation day.
I understand.
What are you doing?
Seeing how many times I can fold a chopstick wrapper.
That's a really good way to spend a day of privation.
The key is folding it into four even parts.
Afterwards,
you can write page numbers on all the pages in Magazine.
Magazine
I'm So Sorry
Hayashi no Ippo
And say “ah” into a fan.
Take the lead out of a pencil.
After that, you can make yourself look like a corpse.
With chalk.
I'm closed in.
That's... Somehow, that's an incredibly proper way to spend a day of privation.
All right, everyone, let's all do it.
Fun, isn't it?
If you're having fun, it's not a proper day of privation.
The pr in privation has to be the pur in purge.
Teacher... have we properly spent a day of privation?
Mita Takoyaki
Coming to the sea on Sea Day is inexcusable to people from those landlocked prefectures.
Can we really call it a day of privation?
You almost get it.
We've deprived ourselves enough.
Is this not a day of privation?
Rental Boat
ved Ice
Have we not deprived ourselves enough?
We attend         an outdoor        school
As I thought, it's impossible to
celebrate Sea Day in the mountains.
Aren't you using a broad definition of
school if you don't mind coming here?
I -am- a school shut-in.
The pr in privation is the same as the pur in purge.
Lake Biwa connects
to the sea
Honsaku-maru
They really do connect.
No self-confidence
Not really feeling loved, even with a lover
Thinks of their own thoughts as meaningless
Cannot express their opinion
Normally watches people's expressions
Do not act unless ordered
Originally published 1st August, Showa 82.
From Chapter 104
Doctor Kahogo
Part 2
An overprotective group?
Well... Protectors tend to be overprotective, don't they.
Curry
Yakisoba
Oyakodon
Tondon
China Don
Gyudon
Shaved
ice menu
Berry  Milk  Lemonade
Pineapple  Dream  Mint
Peach  Coconut  Aqua
You don't look like a protector.
No, Kotonon is very overprotective of her skin.
Blog  Photo   Diary
Sunburn is a net
idol's worst enemy
You certainly are.
You're someone who's amazingly overprotective against sunburn.
You might as well not come to the beach.
So you mean this is a collection of such overbearing protectors?
Well, it is an overprotective group.
What are you overprotective of?
Comics.
Combat Butler Hayachi
This is my copy to save.
Other than this, I have one to read and one to lend out.
After this, if LEs or ones with pack-ins come out, I'll buy three of each of those too.
Monjayaki
Bread
Curry bun
Cheese bun
That's certainly overprotective, isn't it.
Aren't the contents the same?
There's no reason to go along with unsavory sales practices.
Brother, if you say that now, you won't be able to perform unsavory sales practices.
Goku Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei
LE on sale  2008/10/17
Goku Sayonara,
Zetsubou-sensei
LE on sale
2009/2/17
If I were, perhaps, to ever write a book,
I would be happier if the reader treasured their one copy forever.
Still thinking you're the only one favored by God...
If it sells...
Just maybe, if it sells...
Zan Sayonara,
Zetsubou-sensei
DVD vol. 1 on
sale sometime
in 2009
By the way, brother, this belongs to Fujiyoshi, one of your students.
Commencing armed intervention to
end all warfare with Gundam
She cut it out of a magazine and laminated it.
That's overprotective too, isn't it.
About what you just said, with the “that too”.
There's a song registered with the exact same lyrics.
Pay up for the reproduction rights to the music.
Hey, you.
About the design of your hakama.
There's no way we -couldn't- consider it an infringement on one of our company's character designs.
Pay up.
Aren't you being overprotective of your copyrights!?
There are plenty more overprotective people here.
Overprotective people who wear white gloves while playing with their toys!
Those who are overprotective of problematic cabinet ministers!
Those who watch cosmetics drop by drop!
I don't fit in with these people!
I'm gonna go take a swim!
How completely out of context.
Very well. Then I'll go over there.
NO
SWIMMING HERE
NO SWIMMING
OVER HERE,
EITHER
NO SWIMMING
Isn't this overprotective!?
Just where am I supposed to swim!?
Over here!
That's narrow!
What're those!?
KEEP OUT
They've been increasing thanks to overprotection.
The sea is no fun anymore!
I'm going to the park!
Suspicious
persons
are common!
Demolish
Where are the rides?
They're dangerous, so we've removed all of them.
Do Not Drink
Beware of Suspicious Persons!
Demolish
-All- of them!?
That's just dodging responsibility in the name of being protective!
There's so, so much overprotection in the world!
If you fluff things up by being too overprotective,
doesn't that just make everyone like them less!?
erryZ
The crazy fans scare the newbies off!
Excessively being selected for the All Stars is frowned upon!
Zetsubou Broadcasting
Making the locals shudder during a pilgrimage!
Laughing too much during a Kudo Kankuro movie, making it dull for the other patrons!
Since everyone is overprotective, it drives down interest!
Having learned that lesson, I dissolve my contract with my body double at once!
Teacher.
This old lady wants to thank you.
Thank me?
Thank you so much for visiting grandpa's grave.
Er, umm...
Teacher, you must be a muscleman.
The body double did it, huh.
Just what did that body double do?
It wasn't me!
It was the idiocy of someone who resembles me!
You're the best!
If only we had gotten a teacher like you sooner, we—
Er, hello?
Just what did that body double—
Are you sure you're okay with me?
That body double!
Grilled Millet
The fireworks are starting.
What? What did he do to cause this!?
Kamaage
Atsuage
Kakiage
Shaved Ice
Butt Bugs
Sukiyaki
Feels good man
Yakitori
Bite what?
Pure Water
Grilled Mokomichi
Decor
Yakitori Hyo-chan
Made in China
I had so much fun today!
Doing what?
Shall we make you happy?  Find your way to our door
Welcome to our grand reopening
Our clothing clings precariously to our shoulders
For now, forget everyday life
Wipe off the night dew and come in
A still-beating heart?  Blue, and done rare?
It fits well with what you really mean
Poison and lies become our habitual spices
Stick a fork in your unsatisfied sadness
It's fine if you leave what you don't like, just like a child
It'll cheer you up, make you feel better bite by bite
I wave and smile, saying "see you next week"
One-night-only cash
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Voltes V,
Haru Urara, JASR*C, or copyright on a rodent is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou  Sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Let's draw stealthily and match the song, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Tanii Asuka
Sanada Asami
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:
Enomoto Shunji
Let's despair over the next volume too!