The story until now.
"The culprit is among us,”
said Madame Mantis.
Nozomu, hearing this, awakens in the lobby of an old Western mansion.
In his right hand is a paper knife stained red with blood.
In his left a ticket to Senior Freeter Night.
Thinking that, with an abundance of evidence, he can catch the true culprit,
he heads to the place written on the ticket, Shinjuku Loft Plus One.
Raised on an unexpected dance platform,
even though he is questioned in an
interview setting about metrosexualism,
the large-eared crowd in the VIP box chant for him to leave.
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
So
just
everybody
sing!
It's just
as you think
Even if I find
someone singing
I can't fall in
love right away
Maybe just
not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since you
can't stop
your thoughts
Believe, and
yell out the
password
The password
That everything
will change if
we sing together
Change, fly,
I'm flying
Who do you
want to show
this new you?
To the guy
that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit
of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la
for sure
If it's with
you, that's
the password
Apple
Picking
Beam!
But no matter
where I go, it's
always the same
You're always
there waiting for me
Recruiting citizens
the proper equipment for watching anime
socks: black or navy
necktie: the more garish the better
prevents pimples
When watching anime, wear proper clothes and sit properly.
How to watch Sayonara,
Zetsubou-sensei:
1st pass, watch
2nd pass, pause and understand
the contents
If you can't understand, connect
the nearby conversation, actors,
and recent news.
3rd pass, rewatch understanding
the contents.
Buy three DVDs, one to watch,
one to save, and one to
take with you.
Originally published 24th September, Showa 83.
From Chapter 154
She who Has
Go Go Fight Pro Baseball Relay!
Pro Baseball relay
From the bottom of your heart!
Weekly
Shonen Magazine
DO  0-0 HOK
Top of the 6th
And they enter the 6th with the score still nothing.
I think he lives another life.
Top of the 6th
DO  0-0 HOK
King Records
Here comes the pitch!
What do you mean?
DTV Demonstration
From here,
analog will change to digi
White
Top of the 6th
DO  0-0 HOK
Sa           Zetsubou-sensei
Analog
Oh, wow. Even though he's a top-notch pitcher, he looks like a model.
Drugstore Dr
That's why I think so.
Chinese Restaurant
Obama Ramen
Akamatsu-ya
Chinese Restaurant
Obama Ramen
Akamatsu-ya
Boutique
Obama Ramen
Aka
Boutique
Akamat
Akamats
What if just because of his talent for baseball,
Akamat
Akam
his potential for a fabulous life as a model has gone to waste?
Isn't pro baseball successful enough?
Open at 6PM
achinko
We don't know if he would have been even more of a success as a model!
If he hadn't have played baseball,
Paris Collection
we may have seen Darvish shine even brighter!
Ganaha from the J-League, too;
were he only not so talented at soccer!
I'm sure he would be a great success as a member of Da Pump!
Even Shokotan, were she not so cute!
Nowadays, unmistakably, as a cover author for Magazine J, she'd sell over 50,000,000 books total!
Combined sales 50,000,000
Author's Photograph
Mansion in Kichijoji
Even though their lives may be fabulous, they had other lives too.
bako
achinko
Thinking of it is somehow heartrending.
If Manabe's breasts were bigger,
maybe she could've made it as a TV announcer.
No boobs!
Fujiwara Tofu
Newsstand
Tsuru
You've grown up, Majiru.
Really?
Melancholy of Majiru!
Melancholy of Majiru
Depression
number 42
Killifish brothers
Melancholy of Majiru
Depression
number 42
Killifish brothers
Depression
number 42
Killifish brothers
Depression
number 42
Killifish brothers
Majiru, when you grow up, what do you want to be?
Kids say the darnedest things.
No, really!
This is a bit sudden, but I have some Western-style sweets.
Newsstand
Tsuru
A
Recruiting
Production staff
Cast
People with meek
hopes for budget
Sha
Would you like some?
Hey, these are really tasty!
Game
Fuji-ya
Aren't they?
Phoenix Sushi
Sushi
The boss of that place made them.
The guy from the sushi restaurant?
His sushi's incredibly tasty.
Game
Fuji-ya
But what if he wasn't any good at making sushi? See?
They say that heaven grants you only one gift.
But in reality, some people get two or three.
That messes up the proverb!
All of you with two or three gifts!
Go back to properly having one, like heaven granted you!
Shall I make your body unable to play baseball!?
Nebata Hardware
Hold it!
π Touch
Or would you like to have the kind of face they can only draw in the comics!?
Ohno
Drugs
Cafe
Don't!
The possession of blades over 5.5cm (including spades and knives) is forbidden
Violators may be detained or fined.
Chiri, you're too quick to violence.
It's only cut 38!
Even if you don't do that, Kitsu, Japan will be fine.
It's not that heaven won't give you two gifts,
but that society will refuse to recognize two gifts!
The public determine society!
Japanese love that kind of compartmentalization!
They won't recognize a second gift that also pops up!
Taruki-tei
Special Price
You'd think he could be a #4 pitcher even in the pros.
But society surely won't accept it!
Special Price
When Ichiro wanted to pitch at the All-Star game, he was criticized for being rude!
Even though his fastball is nearly 150km/h!
Kitchen   Kainan
Phoenix Sushi
Sushi
And the boss of that place, were he to put these Western sweets out officially,
even if it didn't change, he'd be criticized for letting the quality of his sushi drop, wouldn't he.
I kind of get it.
Ramen
Obama Ramen
Chinese
Ramen
Obama Ramen
Chinese
Ramen
Obama Ramen
Chinese
Ramen
Obama Ramen
Chinese
Ramen
sushi Furniture
Obama Ramen
Chinese
sushi Furniture
Obama Ramen
Chinese
sushi Furniture
But there's plenty of multi-talents on TV. Aren't they recognized?
Sakura
Well,
None of their talents are recognized!
Phoenix Sushi
Sushi
I thought I was going to say it!
Because they do plenty, but it feels like it can all be summed up.
Hey, hey.
• Taiwan + sweets + Nagura + sailor uniform
• Singer + Hokkaido + fresh caramel
• Lyrics + basis for anime + gourmet book
• Cuisine + singing + comedian
• Idol + foul-mouthed + thief
• Actor + lewdness + bottomless
• Gag + moe + societal commentary
+ self-criticism + Japanese paper
+ added cuts + OAD + blog + redraw
• Stop the useless animation production
+ protect "Quickening" with all your might
• Inoue Kikuko + age 17
Yes, a second talent that springs up truly won't be recognized.
This is the tragedy of those who have too much!
I wanted to see their other lives, too!
They sound interesting.
A
7/12 is the day of elections to the Tokyo Municipal Assembly.  Don't stay home and play games, go vote.  The right to complain about the government belongs to those who vote.
You were there?
Always.
I don't know if you can see it on days like today.
Ah, there it is.
Sanada
Chinese Restaurant
The Twin Towers of Talent.
One tower is for talents accepted by society.
Free market
7/11
Koishikawa
The other tower is for talents left unshown.
If we go there,
the White
Dragon
seeks foes
Gemini
we'll be able to see the other talent of those gifted twice!
Let's go!
That day is soon
You're just as strange as Tamori.
Koishikawa Shop
Sure am.
Tower of Druaga
Entrance
Everyone, behold!
That's!
Ichiro the pitcher!
I almost gave up!
And Suzuki the announcer, popular among kids as a pro gamer!
Master Higgins
Game only an hour a day
Yes, this is a place where second talents that weren't let out into the light of society can blossom.
Welcome!
Isn't it great, boss?
Here I can use all the cream I want, like I love to do!
That's!
A
, it seems,
will launch 7
artificial satellites.
If he didn't become a politican, just like that,
we'd have been able to see Putin take gold!
And if Kazushige hadn't played baseball,
wouldn't he have made a wonderful fighter?
With those muscles he'd have been quite pressed.
What muscles?
Pro baseball
Sportscaster
Talent
Karate master
Actor
Has a great dad
Voice actor
Seven Crowns
You can see other second talents, too!
China
supporter
China-lover
If he didn't become Japan's PM,
he'd have blossomed as a Chinese politician!
Sakiyomi
Without her extraordinary kiss power,
she'd have blossomed as a newscaster!
Capital!
If he didn't do track and field,
he'd have an investment office in the Hills!
Tempai, quick rea, yay, yay
no such thing
No animals
If he didn't tame animals,
he'd have made a name for himself as a pro mahjong player!
Not gonna
buy Famitsu
anymore
If it had used DVDs!
Stupid! Don't get
the wrong idea!
If it had been based on the game!
Damn you
Kumeta, lol
If it had been produced by Kyoto!
Devilish ten weeks
If it had been serialized by Company S!
I'm a winner!
A better man!
If he hadn't become assistant to the wrong man!
So, shall we go to the next floor?
Room of Dilemmas
Here, those who have the dilemma of opposite talents
can allow their unshown talent to blossom!
She's a top-class SM queen, but!
She also has potential to be a top-class masochist!
Love it!
X has 15 million fans!
But her clients don't recognize it!
Well, I guess.
By becomeing a top-class masochist?
doesn't that make you not a top-class sadist?
That's why her talents cause a dilemma!
There are more capabilities that cause dilemmas here!
A clever airheaded celeb!
Ummmmmmmm...
An economy sedan that goes fast if you floor it!
Certainly, for any of them, the appeal of one side damages the image of the other.
A
In the end, only
those with strong
luck win at mahjong.
It's like how hamburgers targeted at health fanatics didn't sell.
Premi
It truly can be thought of as having too many gifts.
You're lucky to have been spared from having any.
A
Best lead actor
Best personality
Finished outside the ranks of
"mai hasubando"
for performance in:
Gunda* 00
Macros F
etc.
A
Best lead actor
Best personality
Finished outside the ranks of
"mai hasubando"
for performance in:
Gunda* 00
Macros F
etc.
A
Best lead actor
Best personality
Finished outside the ranks of
"mai hasubando"
for performance in:
Gunda* 00
Macros F
etc.
A
Best lead actor
Best personality
Finished outside the ranks of
"mai hasubando"
for performance in:
Gunda* 00
Macros F
etc.
A
Best lead actor
Best personality
Finished outside the ranks of
"mai hasubando"
for performance in:
Gunda* 00
Macros F
etc.
A
Best lead actor
Best personality
Finished outside the ranks of
"mai hasubando"
for performance in:
Gunda* 00
Macros F
etc.
Hey, that's rude!
Okay, next is the top floor!
The final boss!?
Harumi!
Didn't you take today off from school because of the deadline for your doujin?
Doujin? What's that?
It's this! Have you forgotten!?
Swi      th
Sayonara,
Tieria-sensei
The Fujiyoshi that's here isn't the comics-nerd Fujiyoshi in glasses we're used to.
This is the Fujiyoshi that allowed her second and third talents to blossom!
Amazing!
I'd like a match with the famous sports elite Fujiyoshi!
She took her glasses off!
Those weren't just glasses.
They were also restraints!
If she didn't draw comics!
If she didn't draw comics, Harumi—!
Hidamari Baths
What are you, Gachableep?
Harumi's Room
Comics are interesting too.
Old Testament
New Testament
Secrets of Eva
Ghostory
Sea Story
Rinne
Negima
Hayate
To Loveru
Kodansha
Shonen Maga
Analog
It's pretty slovenly just dropping your glasses.
Heavy!
If you moe for pachi, if
you moe for cell phones, if
even Kumeta moes, a Mini
4WD is added.
Sayo
Zetsubo      ei ep 3
Return to Sender
Era of the
Penguin Characters
Sayo
Zetsubo      ei ep 3
Return to Sender
Sayo
Zetsubo      ei ep 3
Return to Sender
Sayo
Zetsubo
Return to Sender
Sayo
Zetsubo
Return to Sen
Sayo
Zetsubo      ei
Return to Sender
Sayo
Zetsubo      ei e
Return to Sender
Sayo
Zetsubo      ei ep
Return to Sender
Moe trash
Merger?
What
is
this,
the back
of a
flyer!?
Originally published 3rd March, Showa 83.
From Chapter 179
Russian Time Song
You have a cold?
You should take some medicine.
Okay.
Demerol
Did the medicine not work?
It won't work immediately.
My favorite
teacher
Antarctic Adventure
It seems like the medicine's working... I feel a little better.
That's good.
Why didn't it work sooner!?
I did not send out
pictures of naked
boys using the
name "Nami".
I did not send out
pictures of naked
boys using the
name "Nami".
I did not send out
pictures of naked
boys using the
name "Nami".
I did not send out
pictures of naked
boys using the
name "Nami".
I did not send out
pictures of naked
boys using the
name "Nami".
I did not send out
pictures of naked
boys using the
name "Nami".
I did not send out
pictures of naked
boys using the
name "Nami".
Isn't that surprising!?
There's a time lag between taking the medicine and when it works.
Well, it's not limited to medicine; generally, things have—
A time lag.
Like broadcast of anime out in the boonies,
Kanagawa
Sa
Su
Chiba TV
TeleTama
Mo
Sun TV
Tu
TV Aichi
We
Kyoto
Th
Fr
Mew
or the time between pressing the button on a digital camera and when the shutter actually closes,
or the time between when you eat and when you feel full.
Gyoza
Order's ready
That kind of normal time lag occurs,
but beyond that,
Gyoza-no-Ohshu
Food Place
I love You
Photo
Memories
Studio Kanon
Piano Lessons
Photo Studio
New
Dragon
gon
Kirara
damari Wind
Aoki Ume
Monthly
Uniform Feature!
Coat VS. Blazer
AniNerd
Moe song
chorus!
Flower and
Flower
Girl
Patrons, please refrain from standing and reading the magazines.
On sale tomorrow
Back-to-school
for first-graders
If you see a
stranger, call 110
Yao*
Southern resort
Departing
Takao
Current stop, Nakano, Nakano
Express
Takao line
Densha ni Go!
there's that.
Eww.
How disgusting! Stop grinning and remembering that.
What do you mean, "how disgusting"!?
Densha ni Go!
Final line
Gyoza-no-Ohshu
Food Place
I love You
Gyoza-no-Oh
Rame
Sale
Sawada Hardware
Har
Gyoza-no-Ohshu
Gyoza-no-Ohs
Ramen
Bar
in stock
oto
I'm Kikuchi Makoto
What are you doing all of a sudden!?
Like you can just shrug it off!
Yesterday...
Sawada Hardware
Sale
Hello!
Sky Drugs
Japanese Sweets
Ume
Man, you sure look like a hardware salesman.
Blue Sky Drugs
Makeup
Japanese Sw
Ume
ue Sky Drugs
Makeup
Yeah, I guess.
Bar
Hidamari Baths
I couldn't think of anything else at the time,
Bishojo
Umemoto
Cafe Laurel
Hanai Stationery
Cafe Laur
Caf
but it had me on pins and needles all night!
What's up with that remembered anger!?
Bar
truments
Gyudon  Yo         ya
Open 24
hours
There are people who have a time lag to anger.
Gyudon  Yo         ya
You were there?
Yes, always.
Salon
Sanada Instruments
Yoshida
Like parents who aren't concerned at all the night before,
Goodnight!
Okay
but the next morning burn with rage.
Good morning!
Sit right there!
Sit right there!!
We have new products!
Car Goods Autowax
Try one!
GPS Corner
Big sale
Would you like to try one?
ce Cream
Tea
How about it?
ce Cream
Tea
Cafe Hi-kara
Golden Ginza  Shopping District
nekawakure Clothes
Tanba Variety
Big sale
Would you like to try one?
Tea
Ir
Irr
Irre
Irres
Irresi
Irresis
Irresist
Irresisti
Irresistib
Irresistibl
Irresistible
Irresistible M
Irresistible Me
Irresistible Mem
Irresistible Memo
Irresistible Memor
Irresistible Memori
Irresistible Memorie
Irresistible Memories
Tea
When I see a dirty book or something at a friend's house,
sometimes when I get home I feel horny.
Trauma High
Is that time lag?
Now that you mention it,
there's things that make me shiver when I remember them later.
When I remember them now, I realize they were pretty dangerous.
Sketching on asbestos with chalk.
Eating plenty of gyoza last year.
Playing with strange adults.
You should realize that about strange adults even then.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
What?
I just remembered that time I insensitively cut in front of you, teacher!
Didn't that trouble you!?
When?
11.7 billion yen for an Atheneum of Animation
Animator's average salary
20s
30s
Six months ago!
Japan's Three
Great Stories
Mahjong Story
S   ea Story
G  hostory
Leopard-head Story
5/26
And seven months ago I—
It's fine!
A time-delayed apology?
I want to live entangling my fantasies with reality!
Now that I think of it, there are things I kind of regret.
Come on, why don't you cleanly feel sorry for them then?
So we meet again.
Yesterday I was
the pupil, but today,
I am the teacher.
In one ear and out the other.
Anyway, this world—
is full of time lags!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Gasoline prices on the Turnpike
Gundam before magnet coating
Submarine patents
The Los Suspicion
So*y Timer
New words in the Kojien dictionary
Lately, the section chief's been saying "oppappi!"
From 3/28 to 7/11
There was a schedule, but not anymore
That day is soon
Fight! What! Life!!
Like the seven-year killer!
What's that?
July
History
70s and before: For children
10s and after
80s: For manchildren
90s: As an investment
00s: To promote publications
pachinko
World End
00s: To promote publications
If you get hit with this move, you don't die right there, but die seven years later!
Well, I guess there was that.
Third season, even though
politely requested
Teacher, that's it.
Third season, even though
politely requested
The staff and fans
both despaired, but
we got one
PaniPoni
What are you doing to the reader!?
It's the seven-year laugher!
7/11
This is no time to be watching anime!
It hits them right in the funny bone,
and makes them laugh seven years later!
Don't forget to laugh seven years from now.
When I'm together with Maeda,
my heart goes pokapoka
Did they rip off
Sun Warrior Pokapoka?
ShinKawo
Beware
of spam
mail
That's meaningless if they don't find it funny now!
Or the other way around.
If they wonder why they found it funny back then...
It's a time lag of several years before they realize it was dull!
Selling to nerds after that delay is the typical state of this industry!
So it's about
Well, in the first place,
Visual cortex
even the human body, between the time the eyes see something and when the brain recognizes it,
has a time lag. I wonder how long it is.
It's a U-boat!
Thus, even the landscape we see here is from the past!
Looking at you like this, even Kitsu is from the past!
So the current Kitsu
We support Hayate in '09
Past
may even be like this!
Do your best
Present
Misawa
You wore the crowns of courage,
passion, and splendor.(; ;
What a time lag!
The landscape I see may even be like this now!
A comic animated
three times
The comic you're reading now may be old,
and by now really be like this!
Your favorite anime company
Kyoto
shaft
Other
Gunma ward - Pen name Hope
Thank you for reading.
Please look forward to Kumeta Kouji's next
Bwahaha.
It's over!
Ugh
A comic which can
survive the ten
weeks of fear
I'm in despair!
This world full of time lag has left me in despair!
I want to be Orihime someday soon, too
It's nothing to despair about.
There's reverse time lag, too, after all.
Didn't we use
this joke before!?
When there's a baby in her before the wedding!
Carelessly compressing
Carelessly splitting
Carelessly putting it up on the 'net
It's all careless
When it's leaked on the net before it goes on sale!
IX is kinda like hanafuda
Guessing he should buy some shares
Knowing what stocks will go up before it happens!
That's no good either!
Time lag occurred here.
The gag is seven years later.
What a time lag!
Seven years from now, won't Enari be 30 years old?
When we storyboarded, we had just won the WBC.
But putting that kind of gag on the air now is too chilly.
Having too loose of a schedule is a problem.
Oh, looks like the revised law on child pornography passed.
I'm Tanaka Yoko!
A gag came from seven years ago!
From 2001
Pets
Travel
Outdoors
Finding one's true self
Aura Soma
Yoga
From Chapter 103
Originally published 25th July, Showa 82.
Withering Heights Part 2
Looks like someone’s getting on.
Kimura, are you on a journey of self-discovery too?
I wouldn't take that kind of illogical trip.
I'm just going on vacation.
Nyon
Kaere, save me!
He's trying to talk to me in English!
Can't you speak English too?
Show the Full Moon
Waldo
I don't understand what this person is saying in English.
I'm gonna sue you!
He doesn't get Kaere's English?
So she's displayed her mastery of English.
There are plenty of people who, though they seem fluent in English practice,
display their true mastery of the language when they travel overseas.
Especially English teachers.
Well, I'm sure Kaere is a girl from somewhere other than the Anglosphere.
Photograph
of the
deceased,
returned
Schedule
This isn't the bus you take to display yourself.
Entrance
Try Tokyo Station, Yaesu South terminal 1.
What!
Highway Bus
I only ride that in August!
Teacher, let's play a game!
The Yamanote Line game!
Show the Full moon
Here's Waldo
You're showing your sorrowful normalness.
Far and wide, now and then! Red things!
Red.
Anything red is fine, okay?
You were there?
Okay, I'll start.
Tomato.
Bloodsplatter.
Sunset.
Flesh.
Red fox.
Baby.
The Red Baron shows newborn babies.
In a red room behind a red door.
Kitsu, you're showing the darkness of your heart!
Showing yourself isn't necessarily bad.
It can be a brave coming out!
All right, everyone, let's let it all out!
Crisp
When did it get this full?
Who has something to share?
Me!
Crisp
Up until now, I've really been a no-good, negative person who finds no meaning in life!
What do you
have to share?
What do you have to share?
Me!
I put myself on a pedestal, and looked for faults in others!
I was horrible, no-good, worthless human trash!
Just because I got a bit part in an anime, I thought I was popular!
Super
I was mistaken, I'm really just a creepy bald perv!
I mistakenly thought I was cool,
but really, I'm just a guy with a ghoulish jaw!
All of us here today thought we were no-good people.
But Positive Leader has opened our eyes!
By facing reality, you understand how important you are!
We're a family. There's no need to hide our secrets.
Find a shining path to tomorrow in the world!
What kind of self-improvement seminar is this!?
Self-exposition has left me in despair!
Self-published autobiography
Confessing to a crime on TV
Contestants in a hair-growth contest
Marukawa Tamayo's indifference to the election
Taking an obviously-biased TV interview in Akiba
A high-class person's blog
Sato Eri's novel
NHK's syndication in 128 countries
Taking an obviously-biased TV interview in Akiba
A high-class person's blog
Sato Eri's novel
NHK's syndication in 128 countries
Taking an obviously-biased TV interview in Akiba
A high-class person's blog
Sato Eri's novel
NHK's syndication in 128 countries
Taking an obviously-biased TV interview in Akiba
A high-class person's blog
Sato Eri's novel
NHK's syndication in 128 countries
Self-published autobiography
Confessing to a crime on TV
Contestants in a hair-growth contest
Marukawa Tamayo's indifference to the election
Taking an obviously-biased TV interview in Akiba
A high-class person's blog
Sato Eri's novel
NHK's syndication in 128 countries
In these circumstances, we should progress sagely, showing nothing!
Yukorin's canceled
interview
It's over
Michael's face
Manabe's private life on blog
Voice actress's age
Minister of Agriculture's bandage
That all of the staff went backstage to congratulate after the
Regret Recording
Then, I've thought of something good.
Areola Volcano
I've set up a body double of young master.
Who?
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Hello, teacher.
All items
on sale
Hello.
Karaoke
No one's realizing.
Of course, it's a body double.
Drugs
Hey, Nozomu.
You're late, Nozomu.
Oh my, brother.
Like this, Nozomu!
Beware of
suspicious
persons
on campus
Shall we make you happy?  Find your way to our door
Welcome to our grand reopening
Our clothing clings precariously to our shoulders
For now, forget everyday life
Wipe off the night dew and come in
A still-beating heart?  Blue, and done rare?
It fits well with what you really mean
Poison and lies become our habitual spices
Stick a fork in your unsatisfied sadness
It's fine if you leave what you don't like, just like a child
It'll cheer you up, make you feel better bite by bite
I wave and smile, saying "see you next week"
One-night-only cash
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Gachapin, Enari,
or Toshi is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou  Sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Matching the song, let's draw limply, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Asumi Kana
Sawashiro Miyuki
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:
Kurosaki Rendo
Let's despair over the next volume too!