The story so far.
Nozomu was caught up in a red-white liberation protest in Kichijoji that began when it was discovered
that the homeowners association was blocking home construction.
Backing an argument that, if red and white were that hated, Kohaku should be cancelled for New Year's,
Aso said “Nerds should be OK with the tricolor.”
Kohaku had another color mixed in.
But the famous enka singers selected for this new “Tea Green” team, neither the familiar red nor white, raged.
Nozomu, his life and chastity threatened, was in a bind...
Having lived on the run for a year, Nozomu found
himself at a shop called “Allgays 2-chome Sunset”.
A madam resembling Chemistry's
Kawabata says “I preferred the old days.
We didn't have cell phones or pearls or beads, but we had dreams!”
At that moment, an HOA rep appeared
saying “Were you trying to be moving?”!
On her tea-green armband were the words “Wakakusa Four Sisters”...
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
A
LDP Defeat High School
It's an Easter egg.
Which came first, the chicken or the egg?
Where are you going?
Do nerds exist because there is anime
Does anime exist because there are nerds
Do I work on this to live
Do I live to work on this
Are the staff worn out because the schedule is wrecked
Is the schedule wrecked because the staff are worn out
Originally published 8th April, Showa 84.
From Chapter 176
The Egg of the Klak
Night Watch Room
Culture Ministry
Which came first, the shut-in or the house?
The house, of course. Otherwise, they'd have nothing to be shut in.
No, I don't think so.
I think that, long before mankind
began to build houses, shut-ins existed.
In holes in the woods.
In the woods...
Don't open it.
That's a pretty outdoorsy shut-in.
You're not wearing panties again!
Aren't you embarrassed!?
Embarrassed?
Hold on a moment.
This, too, must be questioned.
Which came first, panties or shame?
I'll sue you!
He means, did people start wearing
panties because they were ashamed,
or did people start being ashamed after taking off their panties?
That's right.
Either way, you're not wearing panties.
Don't say weird things like that!
rder
Hey, what's wrong?
Shame came first
For some reason, I suddenly feel ashamed.
You can cover up with this.
I tried putting on a leaf.
Underwear came first
For some reason, I can't take it!
I'm gonna rip it off!
Stop it! I'm embarrassed!
Em...barrassed?
Embarrassed?
Yes. In this world,
there are cases, like the chicken and the egg, where one cannot tell which came first.
Were special interests born because of Parliament, or was Parliament born because of special interests!?
Are comic books published to sell graphic novels,
Fun Fun Fun
or are graphic novels published because issue after issue of the comic piled up?
Was the company named for the place, or the place named for the company?
Ebitsu
Tsuporo
Toyoda
Hitachi Cit
Which came first!?
Trend Egg
Ishikawa
Tamago's Chururun Shop
The Real Pole Group
Science
m Records
ade
granate
Which came first, the idol group or the fans?
Science
S
The Real Pole Group
Science
m Records
ade
granate
You were there?
Yes, always.
Concert
God 2009
N*K Koishikawa Hall
Decade-
later
Concert
Trade
Me!
Today
sold out
Which came first, the idol group or the fans?
The idol group came first and then it got fans, right?
Not necessarily.
It's completely plausible for the fans to have come first.
If they made an idol group with 48 girls, I'd definitely be a fan.
I'll do it!
So fans could have come first.
Fair Trade
Comm
ission
Koishikawa
Mind your Manners
Treasure
That specific!?
You could say it's precisely because of that kind of needy fan that the group exists.
Which came first, S or M?
A star-crossed encounter takes place in the stone age
Well, I guess they could have happened at the same time.
Future Literature
Habitual Shincho
Slow Fiction
Kyukoku Natsuhiko
Zetsubou-sensei
May the world of comics
remain at peace
New last week
Petalico
Train
Comi
Do I not get any because I'm a nerd, or did I become a nerd because I wasn't getting any?
Don't be so naive.
You're a nerd because you're a nerd!
You're not getting any because you're not getting any!
Fan
Rowd
Shinko
Ino Cafeteria
As well as things where it isn't obvious what came first,
Magma
hiring
part-
time
Magma
Magma B
there are things where what came first is well-known but the truth is murkier.
Magma
Magma Bu
For example, which came first, the
hamburger steak or the hamburger?
It's gotta be the hamburger steak, no matter how you look at it.
Ancient Germany
I haff kreated dis ting kalled der hahmburker,
but I vould much like to put zometing betveen it.
Vat if ve place betveen it zome grount meat?
Du are a jenius!
Und ve shall kall dis meat die hamburk steak!
Ja vohl!
Teas of the World
Fish
Beef
Veggies
Teas of the World
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Fish
Beef
Teas of the World
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Fish
Teas of the World
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Teas of the World
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
For example.
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
It's just a bun when it's got nothing between it!
ma Burger
There're other examples.
Ancient England
It's tea time, old chap.
Tea time indeed.
I say, do you perhaps feel a trifle parched whilst eating scones?
As if one's mouth were withering.
Mayhap 'twould behoove us to place in hot
water some leaves, and henceforth drink it?
Brilliant!
As it is a refreshment for tea time, we shall refer to it as tea!
Indeed!
Maybe they made tea because of tea time!
Takemori Teas
Teas of the World
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Teas of the World
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Teas of the World
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
Upstairs
rooms
for rent
Takemori Teas
No way!
Ministry of Torture General Store
General Merchandise     Foods     Spirits            Pork
Are you saying that Russians are called
that because they play Russian roulette,
and that Mongols are called that
because they do Mongolian chops?
I'm furious! I met a panty thief!
Which came first, panties or panty thieves!?
Sweets
Panties came first. Otherwise, there wouldn't be any to steal.
No.
I made something interesting out of a skin.
Can we use it for anything?
It's useless.
Oh well. Let's leave it here.
Stop, thief!
What are you even going to use that for after you've stolen it!?
Maybe the panty thief came first, and panties came after!
Cafe
Palace of Culture
Store
Groceries             Candy                Tobacco
That's impossible!
Well, when they were stolen they were nothing but a weird skin.
Which came first, prostration or the earth's surface?
Of course, without the earth's surface, it
would be impossible to prostrate oneself.
No, wait.
It burns!
Maybe prostration came first.
Which came first, hope or despair?
Hope came first, of course.
Coffeeshop
Zetsubou Restaurant
Open
8/5
Sanosuko
prediction
Goldfish
Kiss
Without hope, you can't feel despair.
Zetsubou Restaurant
I don't understand.
I'm so worn out.
I feel like dying.
I'm in despair.
Don't just despair all the time.
How about having a little hope?
Hope?
Hope.
What's hope?
I dunno, it was just on the tip of my tongue.
If I had to think of it, it would be
not despairing, but having wishes...
Hope.
Hope, huh.
That's a nice word.
What a touching ending.
“Hello! Kibou-sensei,”
starring Shimenuno
Nozomu rather than
Itoshiku Nozomu,
will not happen.
Japan, a spy's paradise.
It is said that twenty thousand operatives of a
certain country have infiltrated modern Japan.
They seek to plunge Japanese society into turmoil.
Keyframer is sick
Animation director can't be found
Assistant director is gone
Both chief animation directors are helping out on Ghostory
An earthquake broke an undersea cable, and the data can't get through
With Hidamari, Negima, and Ghostory, deadline for delivery is starting to weigh down on us
Originally published 8th October, Showa 83.
From Chapter 156
A Certain Country You Know Well
Four, five, six...
Huh, two more yen. I know I have it.
Even if she didn't make make such a fuss looking for pocket change, there'd still be a huge line forming behind her.
She's plunging society into turmoil.
This must be the work of operatives bent on disturbing our harmonious way of life!
Now what are you going on about?
the Boss's Onigiri
She's just your everyday troublesome person.
No, if she's holding up this many people,
it causes an accountable loss.
She may be scheming the downfall of Japan as a nation by causing its economy to fall!
The yen is collapsing!
That woman may well be an operative!
If that's true, then isn't this the work of the operatives too?
the Boss's Onigiri
Yesterday at the library...
Koishikawa Library
There were people there who were really breaking everyone's concentration.
I didn't think too hard about it at the time, but...
A couple acting all lovey-dovey at the library...
They must be operatives!
Scheming to weaken the nation's power by lowering the knowledge of the Japanese people!
I've got no motivation
Lowered knowledge
Teacher, if that's true, then isn't this the work of operatives too?
Oden
Lone journey
Dai's
special
boxed lunch
the Boss's Onigiri
Turnstiles
North exit
What's up?
Some idiot clogging things up again.
Pain in the ass.
Something like making turnstiles freeze up is the textbook definition of sabotage!
Operative Maeda
He must be an operative!
That's horrible!
Where's
Sanosuke!
Oden
Then—!
That must be part of an operative's sabotage activities, too.
When someone sitting in front of you has a big head!
Pop Sho
Their objective is to cut off Japan
from the outside world by causing the decline of its anime culture and a decrease in the number of weeaboos!
So many examples come to mind of things which disrupt our harmonious way of life.
60-minute wait
Like when someone's ahead of you in line for every ride you go to!
Or when someone changes your bike to the lowest gear while it's locked up!
We encounter their sabotage every day!
Happy birthday,
Director Shinbo
9/27
China Bun
It's not writing.
Fire
Extinguisher
King
Crab Delivery
I'm sorry, I'm sorry! I must be using it wrong!
King
Crab Delivery
Lemme grab that.
I knew it! It was made in that country!
It's a booby trap!
They're building these as a scheme to paralyze Japan's distribution systems!
Such attention to detail...
You've been in line for a while. Why are you way back there?
I thought I'd make the line shorter for people by leaving.
Next!
Fam
&
Ily Mart
Teacher, it's your turn.
You were there?
Yes, always.
We Take
Suicoca
Kira
That comes to 315 yen.
All right, three hundred...
All I've got is a ten-thousand!
Can you break it?
Boss! I need change!
Secret
Am I an operative too?
Calling them operatives is strange to begin with.
What's with operatives destroying things?
They should make up their minds whether
they're gonna break them or work on them.
It's pissing me off!
Real operatives make things, right?
That's right, Chiri.
Who're they?
Operatives.
It's not like they're here to destroy or sabotage.
They came to Japan to learn how to make things.
Really? What do you want to make?
I would like to make next-generation LCD TVs.
What do you want to make?
I would like to make tasty sweet strawberries.
If you're that fired up to learn, I'll teach you!
I'll pool all my resources and teach you!
Well...
Keep Off Grass
Parks Groundskeeping Dept.
First Where's Sanosuke?
PM Asho's ratings drop!
Down 20% in five months
First Where's Sanosuke?
PM Asho's ratings drop!
Down 20% in five months
Japan's
They were really operatives!
Industrial spies!
nosuke
Japan's
What are you doing leaking our technology!?
Oh my.
You Japanese are too kind.
Missiles heaped full of Japanese
engineering are pointed right this way.
Cannon
State-of-the-art
military equipment
hoping for
another
production
run
I feel like, having taught them in good faith, I've been betrayed.
Well, don't worry about it too much.
I was naïve.
Upon reflection, I must correct my thinking.
Wow, that's unusual.
I made a big mistake thinking they were operatives who operated on things.
I've realized now that they're covert operatives.
But if they're trying to be crafty, why
not introduce them to arts and crafts?
Girls Elementary
glish
vics
Art
Science
Math
Mat
Phys
Civi
We've invited a special teacher for your crafts class today.
Her name is Miss Kitsu.
All right, class.
The body's pressure
points: The head
Faking scandals
Today we'll be studying how to manipulate people through information control.
The body's pressure
points: The head
Faking scandals
How to spread
negative campaigns
Agne
shiba
tiger
How about anonymous publications?
Fun Fun Fun
That's right. It's a bit old-fashioned, but
anonymous publications are a basic method.
Nowadays you can use the internet, too. Though it's easy for you to be tracked, so be careful.
Where's the art in this?
Maybe those submarine blueprints?
Next time, let's study “How to Endure the Rack 101”.
Selling a '13
Model G
tractor
There are certainly teachers who are "hard at work” every day.
For this month's lessons on “operations”, let's go to an amusement park and sketch.
100 points.
How much can I break labor laws
How far can I stretch the schedule
How short can I cut my sleep schedule
How long can I put off paying my premiums
How little can I pay for food
How much longer can I keep up this line of work, I wonder
Originally published 4th February, Showa 84.
From Chapter 169
Jeremy Thatcher, Dracon Hatcher
Part 2
A
Hogwarts School of
Witchcraft and Wizardry
What?
How far will shut-ins go to buy Jump?
That's not very much range, even for a shut-in.
Give me a break!
I can at least manage a birdie!
By the way, this is how to keep score.
Bogey
Par
Birdy
Eagle
If the zashiki-warashi leaves, the school will crumble!
Oh no, I forgot! Someone stop her!
You all have such amazingly short ranges.
Brother, you've got no room to talk.
There you go.
What's up with this?
Did I remember to turn off the gas?
Did I turn it off!?
Oh my. You don't have any range at all.
I've double-checked, so I'm fine now.
This time I'll get a lot further.
Did I lock the front door!?
I knew you wouldn't make it.
I'm just nervous about it!
Everyone just has their own personal ranges.
What's your range!?
If it's like drivers in golf,
it's best to get as close as possible on the approach shot.
As close as possible?
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Sale
Yasuniku
Karaoke cafe
Kokuenraku Store
Ark
Cafe
That man's got a nice close approach.
How much adultery can you commit nearby!?
What will
Japan do
That's a bit close.
Real go-getter wives do it when their husbands are gone! They do it right at home; that's a nice approach!
That's a hole-in-one!
There're things where you can't have a close approach!
Right now, I'm closest to the pin.
Nice
shot!
Golf is Fun
No, I'm closest to the pin.
When did you—!?
I knew this was why a bed I didn't
order got delivered a few days ago!
Closeness.
No matter how physically close you are, it doesn't matter.
You've got to be close psychologically.
Teacher's subconscious
I'm closest to the pin.
That's dangerous.
International Airport
Late night, at midnight,
waiting for the night train
Crabwalking on
the cliff-like platform
A life that can fit
into a single suitcase
You, my dear, are
the treasure I chose
Close your eyes and softly whisper
The mantle of Hades will envelop us
You, of all people,
I won't let go on ahead
Let's go on a voyage
Okay, give me your hand
If I'm a slave to my fate,
today's the day I'll
fabulously turn traitor
If death is eternal
I don't care if your holding
on slows me down, let's go
I love you, mon amor
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual John Brookfield,
David Papineau , Aki**** Atsushi, or
Jong-nam is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou-sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Matching the song, let's draw illustrations, okay?
Yo, yo, a tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
The eel...
Grins!
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Hurry!
Two puddles were made.
Too big!
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Mizushima Takahiro (Kudo)
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Mizushima Takahiro
Sugita Tomokazu
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Weekly Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei Review
Kudo Jun
Kitsu Chiri
Good morning!
On this program, we respond to the
viewers' various opinions and criticisms
of Zan Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei.
Kudo Jun
Kitsu Chiri
This is the first letter.
These are the thoughts of “Kumagoro” from Tokyo.
A
Making the third season true to the original, whether it's good or bad, is too cautious. Can't you be more experimental? The experimental eps in S2 were great.
Making the third season true to the original, whether it's good or bad, is too cautious.
Can't you be more experimental?
The experimental eps in S2 were great.
Kudo Jun
Kitsu Chiri
Thanks for your thoughts.
Producer Miyamoto Junnosuke would like to give a positive response to this thought.
Kudo Jun
Kitsu Chiri
It the process of producing Zan Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei, we have attempted to incorporate all your ideas,
and hope that you will continue to be so helpful in future projects.
Let's move on to the next letter.
This is from “MAEDAX R”.
C-part of ep 4 had a huge flashback. Wasn't there enough to work with?
A
C-part of ep 4 had a huge flashback. Wasn't there enough to work with? Please publish this anonymously.
MAEDA X
Kudo Jun
Kitsu Chiri
Thanks for your thoughts!
In response to this, Producer Miyamoto Junnosuke says
there's plenty of anime getting rave reviews, like Evangelion: 2.0 You Can (Not) Advance,
so you can go watch those.
Kudo Jun
Kitsu Chiri
We don't have time to read all the letters we've received on the air,
but here's a sampling of them.
You say you're staying true to the original but you're going in completely different directions sometimes.
The DVDs aren't gonna sell.
Of all the places to play around, why the ending credits?
There won't be a fourth season, will there?
And many thoughts like those.
Kudo Jun
Kitsu Chiri
Thank you all so much for your thoughts.
Moving on, having considered your thoughts,
we would like to use them in further production.
Please continue supporting Zan, Sayonara Zetsubou-sensei.
Weekly Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei Review
Illustration:
Kamijo Atsushi
Let's despair over the next volume too!