The story until now.
Nozomu, convinced that this country must change, travels to America to study modern policy.
But what awaited him was the harsh racial discrimination of being judged as a viewing-type eroterrorist.
“Wasn't I a viewing-type eroterrorist the second I saw Yingling!?
By that standard, Japanese middle-school boys are all terrorists!”
He was told firmly,
“The American government does not negotiate with terrorists”,
his letter of recommendation was rejected, and he was imprisoned in Alcatraz.
Despairing Nozomu's cellmate,
Bob the academic leftist in a Guevara t-shirt, struck up a conversation.
“After all, the post-Shogunate history of Japan was constructed by Shiba Ryotaro, right?”
he bluntly proclaimed.
“His white hair is so cool,”
Nozomu said with all his might.
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
A
Looking for Sponsors
2-VI
Good morning, class.
Isn't there something different about him?
His glasses!
Keyframers aren't answering their phones anymore
AD isn't reading the storyboards
Production manager lost the cut bag
Finisher is scary
Art director is scary
Filmer is scary
Originally published 7th March, Showa 82.
From Chapter 86
House of the Girl in Glasses
To be honest,
last week I forgot to write scriptures on my glasses,
so the ghosts took them away.
I don't really get what you mean,
but you've stopped wearing glasses, right?
Well, I got some disposable contacts,
so I thought I'd try using those.
That's so not you, Teacher!
I won't accept you like that!
What's she boiling over about?
Everyone chip in! We're buying Teacher some glasses!
I'll go buy them!
A
ISS High
Why did you buy tinted glasses like that?
I thought they'd be cute.
Mysterious, if anything.
Schoolgirls all sell their panties.
What!?
The schoolgirls in Shibuya all whore themselves.
Teacher...
You were there?
Yes, always.
Teacher is wearing tinted glasses.
That's right, when people go by their prejudices and preconceived notions, we call that “wearing tinted glasses”!
Looking
Looking at
Looking at things
through
tinted
Looking at things
through
tinted
glasses
Girls with big boobs are dumb.
The ones with dark nipples are kinky.
Oh, so that's what “tinted glasses” means.
I always thought it was because of how rosy I felt thinking about boys in glasses.
How long have you—!
Computer janitors are all messing with you.
Bureaucrats are all lazy.
You're blaming the glasses, but isn't he just saying what he wants to?
It's not Teacher's fault! The tinted glasses are making him say it!
How about this?
arc finished
Teacher, do you remember what just happened?
Well...
You said...
I said something that horrible!?
Anime is for little kids.
Temps quit after three months.
Shunsuke doesn't run.
Labor unions are left-wing.
...and stuff!
You didn't say that.
Is it really because of these?
Japs all live in goddamn rabbit hutches.
I knew it.
She always says that kind of thing.
Where did you find tinted glasses this dangerous?
I'll show you.
As worn by Radcliffe
Melon Murata
Welcome.
I'm the owner, Sabae.
Free Po
What are you doing selling tinted glasses like this!?
They're tinted glasses. Of course they're like that.
We have plenty, so feel free to take your time looking.
Early Showa
There are a kind of retro design.
They're early Showa-style tinted glasses.
Back in the kitchen, woman.
They're tinted to that era!?
Ultra
Love
Nowadays, only politicians say things like that.
These are womens' tinted glasses from the early '90s.
They make her eyebrows look thick!
If he's not rich, tall, or Ivy League, I don't want him.
Are those tinted glasses from the bubble era!?
Ultra
Love
Free pouch
There were plenty of tinted glasses back then.
Then again, there are plenty of varieties from every era.
The ones from the war are especially dangerous. Please don't put them on.
Do people buy these tinted glasses?
Thanks to the glasses boom nowadays, they're selling great.
I've taken advantage of it and put out this book.
Monthly
Boys in Tinted Glasses
Special
Nasty old guys
in tinted glasses
I put together a book of guys
who look like they look at life through tinted glasses.
Does that even sell?
Honestly, it hasn't been doing that well.
Hey, some of these are kind of cute!
Mind if I try them on?
Go right ahead.
Wait! Don't look at yourself!
Creepy nerd.
What did I just call myself!?
That kind of thing happens when you look at yourself with tinted glasses.
Is that how society looks at me!?
That had a pitiful result.
Maybe I should get myself some trendy tinted glasses.
Oh, you were there?
I told you...
You horny bald bastard.
What did I just say about myself!?
I told you not to look at yourself with tinted glasses on!
Hey, these aren't glasses.
Those are tinted headphones.
Huh? What're those?
Tinted headphones impose prejudices on what you hear.
How's this?
Only longhairs
listen to rock
Those are pretty old headphones.
I'll pass
on enka
Well, people do have prejudices about music.
I'll pass
on enka
Anime songs
shouldn't
chart
Anime songs
shouldn't
chart
Anime songs
shouldn't
chart
Anime songs
shouldn't
chart
(lol)
J-rap (lol)
Oh, and this is a tinted mouth guard.
It puts your preconceptions on what you taste.
ta Osa
Ramen
Charsiu
Leek
Chain restaurant ramen sucks.
Yeah, there are people who think the chains are all bad.
As they get older, the tints seem to get lighter.
Of course. Back then people didn't have as much information;
as people learn more and more, the tint gets lighter.
Even when experts get together and can't decide, sometimes kids get together and figure it out. That kind of thing.
Even if you don't buy from me, aren't you all already wearing tinted glasses?
I can see it.
That's right.
Now, we must all take off our tinted glasses of prejudice.
Wait, even for that kind of thing!?
I must.  I must remove my tinted glasses.
It's a whole new emotion...
No matter how I look at it, you're into that kind of thing.
You're just looking at it through tinted glasses!
Teachers are all leftists.
All of them.
Hito
Lunchtime is an exciting red black black red yellow black normal black black red reminiscence red black red red
You got black normal red
Come on, red black black Nami line
Man, this's dull.
The author
wasn't ready in time
for this to be in a GN.
Since we couldn't
get a title page yet,
we made our own.
Originally published 3rd June, Showa 84.
From Chapter 183
Progress in Confinement
Apology
A
Flu High
Flu
Warning:
Be careful
of
colds!
Kaga
Class has some time off.
Night Watch Room
Did something happen?
Zan
You'll find out when you get older.
I'm so bored I could die.
That's it! I'll give someone a call!
Status
Edit
Ohkusa    Manami
Home
Mobile
Ringtone
Default
Mobile
Favorites
Clock
eypad
Keypad
Sanosu
Hi!
Hi, Ohkusa, are you doing anything right now?
Sorry, I'm so busy!
What's up with her?
Rush work, rush work.
That's it, I'll go to karaoke!
Hello?
You're right in your house, right?
Of course I am, Chiri.
Okay. I'll be checking up on you in an hour.
Feint.
Now I'm too scared to go out!
I'm bored.
Unfortunately, you cannot leave your house.
But this place is so cramped!
You yourself wanted to play at being the poor student.
That's right.
It's fine as long as I never leave the estate.
I have purchased the neighbors.
Excellent work, Tokita.
If I can't leave my house, then I'll simply buy out the neighbors, and add them to my estate!
Ah, how pleasant.
You're right in your house, right?
Of course! I'm right in my own room.
I'm not lying, am I?
Of course not.
Wow, there's a shop like that around here?
Ramen...
What a refreshingly proletarian meal! I simply must have it!
But they don't appear to deliver.
I want it!
I want it! I want it!
Hold on a moment.
Itoshiki
house
Sold
City Hall
Park
Sold
Ramen
joint
Police
Library
If we simply purchase the neighboring houses in order like this,
Itoshiki
house
Sold
City Hall
Park
Sold
Ramen
joint
Police
Library
I believe we can reach the ramen joint.
Hito
What's this? Such a funny pose.
Is this a new diet?
It's because you sent my wall flying!
This is now part of Our estate.
Begone.
What do you mean!?
This is grounds for legal action!
Have your lawyer explain it to you later.
No, explain it to me now!
Is wanting some ramen that bad?
Ramen?
To be continued
159th
Fi
eld
Day
Beat red!
Beat red! Beat red!
Smash red!
If you lift your leg like that, people will see your panties!
Eww, they're staring at me.
They're the kind that are supposed to be seen! You're just looking for an excuse to be angry!
Human
Failure
Teacher...
He's not looking at me!
Perhaps I should try to find fault.
Human Failure
The Komei Shingon, naturally
Originally published 5th November, Showa 83.
From Chapter 159
The Clothing
Seen by the
Sage Leglipht
Casval Children
Lately, people have often do things that are bad ideas specifically to be called out.
Like idols who deliberately flash their panties to get their fans' attention!
Politicians who make comments knowing they'll be criticized!
Sharapova putting on fake nipples to make people think they can see through!
A
W A O I
I can see
her nipples
We can see her nipples!
I can't see it as anything but deliberate provocation!
Complainery Entrance
I said Osim.
Blonde pig!
That's gotta be intentional.
Complainery Entrance
mabuki High
Yamabuki High
Koike Teppei should play me.
No way!
Oh man, she went for it.
That's right, there's a lot of casting choices that make you think they're trolling.
Things like A-bleep-hime must have seemed the same way at the time.
Digital broadcast test
Hey, look at that Miya-bleep Aoi.
too cute!
Oh no!
Hm, someone's trolling over there too.
Our unreleased single leaked onto the net!
It's such a failure!
You did it on purpose!
A horrible bug has occured in our program.
If you input a certain command,
the mosaics go away.
Please don't do this.
It's a horrible bug.
You had to have done that on purpose!
Definitely.
The best we can do is attempt to determine when someone's intentionally trolling,
and when they're just naturally provoking.
I couldn't eat my pizza! Give me my money back!
This is natural...
Of course! No need for a receipt.
And this has to be on purpose.
How about this?
Analog
I'm super-sexy today.
I must be giving
off hormones.
I must be giving off hormones.
Pheromones
The things a ditzy celeb gets wrong!
They're obviously trolling!
You mustn't spoil them.
How about that?
Name
Johnny Depp
That's right, the weird names people give their kids.
Oh well, with him it's gotta be natural.
It's okay to call him out on it, but you might get smacked.
At this point, I'd have to call them all traps.
I'm in despair.
The amount of deliberate trolling lately has left me in despair!
Complainery Exit
And now, a troll line dance is starting!
If I bite, I lose! I've got to run away!
Tour
Tickets
All onigiri \100
Tour
Tickets
All onigiri \100
Tour
Tickets
All onigiri \100
Tour
Tickets
All onigiri \100
Tour
Tickets
A certain sports newspaper's headline!
If I bite, I lose!
chinko
A neon sign that never gets fixed!
They're just waiting to crack a joke!
But falling for it even when you know
someone's trolling is a sign of kindness.
You were there?
Yes, always.
shita Electronics
It's coming!
Digital
Take a look at the MPs chosen to represent the country.
Sale
\
Oh, cup noodles?
Those are like ¥400, right?
Analog
They're kind enough to take the bait over and over.
Normal people are too busy to do that.
Well, that's for sure.
An idiot trolling or an idiot biting
If they were both idiots, it wouldn't be a troll
What do you mean, Rin?
The one who's trolling is the one who benefits, right, Brother?
On the other hand, the one being trolled isn't
even just taking a risk. It's sure they'll get caught.
Like if you get sweet-talked in by a sting operation!
You're under arrest!
Or if you buy in thinking the market's hit bottom, but it finds a second or third bottom!
Why don't you buy in?
yen
Or Kinsei Middle School, pitching just the
way the batter likes it in order to get data!
Or allowing yourself to be attacked as an excuse to get into the war!
How fearsome!
Complainery Entrance
Everyone, rather than being caught by trolls,
you should start trolling to avoid it!
I always have.
I think that just came naturally.
But it's even worse when you finally do it and you get ignored.
I'm sure one of our kind readers will bite!
There!
Memories
It may be hard to understand,
but everyone's trolling a little.
Come on, everyone, you aren't lifting your legs high enough!
Do it higher, like we practiced!
I can't do it any higher!
Do it!
If your body's too stiff, use the sand curse.
Don't you know?
It's how they make bodies flexible right after death.
You wash sand from deep in the mountain valleys with pure spring water,
over the span of a week dry it atop a rock 100 times,
and chant the incantation while waving a foot-long pomegranate tree wand over the sacred artifact.
Um... hello?
That's too high!
There are trolls so deep no one can even bite.
Like Yasuha's faxes...
All right, everyone, lift them as high as you can!
It's not good! It's so high it can't be grabbed!
What are you saying!?
He caught it!
You thought no one could catch your leg!
You were wrong!
You were wrong about that!
It's like they're doing it in another dimension.
By the way, usually if a stranger showed up at field
day and grabbed a girl's leg, he'd be arrested, right?
Late night, at midnight,
waiting for the night train
Crabwalking on
the cliff-like platform
A life that can fit
into a single suitcase
You, my dear, are
the treasure I chose
Close your eyes and softly whisper
The mantle of Hades will envelop us
You, of all people,
I won't let go on ahead
Let's go on a voyage
Okay, give me your hand
If I'm a slave to my fate,
today's the day I'll
fabulously turn traitor
If death is eternal
I don't care if your holding
on slows me down, let's go
I love you, mon amor
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Saba* city
(Fukui prefecture), Kawa***** Mitsuro, or Bakuman is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou-sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Matching the song, let's draw artistically, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Koyasu Takehito
Ueda Yuji
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration: Nihonbashi Yowoko
Let's despair over the next volume too!