The story until now.
Infected with the mysterious disease “ochappy”, Nozomu is rushed to a sanatorium atop a hill.
Because of that, a large number of phone novel readers who feel the need to pity something flock in chanting
“How pitiful, how pitiful!”
In this atmosphere where they'll be disappointed if he doesn't die,
he learns from a doctor the true name of his disease: “aeromonas”.
He worries daily that everyone associates this disease with a hot date with Mona and he worries daily,
but in reality it's a fish disease so there's something not quite right there.
Now he's inconvenienced.
The audience which expects him to die has come again.
In the end, among them is a former Giocatore on a journey to find himself.
Bringing along TV cameras, he hoists a soccer ball with “Dream” written on the side.
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
A measles epidemic, huh.
You'd better get yourself vaccinated.
Miyo (age 5) over in 3-chome seems to have the measles.
You should go spend the night there and get infected.
Why do I have to go and get myself infected on purpose!?
It's pretty nasty when you get them as an adult,
so they said “Go get measles when you're a kid” in the old days.
But nowadays, you need to do it the right way and go get your shots.
Medically, that's correct, but...
Teacher?
Not just Majiru.
Don't all of you have “measles” that are better to get than not get?
In psychological terms, there's plenty of other things other than just breaking out in measles!
Like what?
For example.
Someone who hasn't played games up until now.
Hey, this is pretty fun!
If they start as an adult and suddenly discover how fun they are,
they'll get completely absorbed and won't be able to focus at work!
My dad's like that!
He never used to play games, but once he picked up a DS, he started having too much fun with it.
And now, every free second he gets, he goes bleep-boop like he's in a nightmare!
Yes, the “measles” you get as an adult are pretty bad.
Planning rejected just before presentation
Scenario changed day-of
Storyboarding: one year
Storyboards done day of ADR
Dubbing the day before broadcast
Delivered just in time for broadcast
Originally published 20th February, Showa 83.
From Chapter 126
The Measles of Madison County
Tomoya!  Grab that ball for—
Canned bread
the Movie
He's got some “measles”!
What the hell is this supposed to be!?
Suddenly becoming obsessed with moe anime after becoming an adult makes a fatal wound.
Leaving things up to your economic strength,
buying all the goods you can whether they're good or bad...
It'll bankrupt your lifestyle!
What's up with those?
She borrowed them from Manseibashi.
Things that don't hurt you very much when you're young
can become fatal if you contract them as an adult!
High school
Those who focus on sports and don't get used to women become infatuated with women after they get recruited into the pros.
pro
They don't practice and their life as an athlete is cut off!
retirement
Even if you think idols are pointless as a boy,
Yurina
Kuma
Enjoy
you'll learn how fun He-bleep Project's concerts are when you become an adult,
blow all your money on their goods,
Solo DVD
and follow them around on tour in a happi coat!
High-five  meeting
Bus tour
If you don't eat canned corned beef,
you'll taste it for the first time as an adult,
Tasty
corned
nom nom
realize how delicious it is,
Tasty
and clog your arteries eating nothing but it!
I'm in despair!
The dreadfulness of late-onset measles has left me in despair!
What's needed is an antibody.
Negative education.
Otonashi?
You want me to follow you?
Kaiichi Seimei
Art Production Mudo
Fashion Salon
Wander
Yakiniku Cowmageddon
Bullets
Kadaruma
Loans
Acomo
Drugstore
Okawari
It's super-moving!
Daily
lunch
menus
What kind of story is it?
I can't stop myself from crying!
Because someone's dying!
So... How are they dying?
They're dying of a disease!
I've never read such a sad story!
Daily
lunch
menus
When people who haven't really read books
grow up and read a phone novel, they call it “super-moving”...
It's sad.
Those kinds of stories are like that too.
Once they start selling, their creators lose their inspiration.
You were there?
Yes, always.
Misdeeds are like that too.
If you're scolded fiercely when you're little and decide not to do it again, it's forgivable,
but as an adult, you'll get arrested right away!
Ding-dong ditch
Prank calls
Writing on people's walls
Skinny-dipping
Touching teacher's chest!
Flipping up skirts!
Peeking in the bath!
Charade
Tai Shoes
Garao
Gyuniku
Restaurant
Summer flower sale
Yakiniku
Hidaruma
Loans
Drugstore
Okawari
Club
So?
If you don't get your boobie-poking out of the way now, Majiru,
Karaoke
you'll get arrested for it as an adult.
Karaoke
Will I be executed!?
Club
Charade
Tai Shoes
Pub Saku
sha II
Lessons
Gara
Summer flower sale
Drugstore
Okawari
Plenty of people have been slaughtered in society for it.
Slaughtered!?
I'll do it.  I'll do it!
François
Birthplace of peace
Used books and more
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
Mahjong
Cheap Snacks
Green Wall Teahouse
But... How?
Amateurs should start with small chests.
Valentine
Family Store
Like this?
Touching
breasts
isn't good.
It's not good.
Touching breasts isn't good.
Looks like he got a good scolding.
But more for something else than for touching.
Looks like it was good medicine for you, Majiru.
I think you've learned not to recklessly touch breasts when you grow up.
I'm depressed.
I want to die.
Oh, I want to die.
Saying you want to die when you're young is like measles.
If you grow up and do it like Teacher,
you'll become that guy who makes everyone around you break out in laughter.
Break out in laughter!?
No way!  I don't want to end up like him!
It's dangerous to take fever medicine when you have measles!
Are you really that far off, Majiru?
Then you've gotta try wanting to die.
Sartre
Welp, guess I should die.
This is a kind of measles it's okay not to have.
Then don't give it to me!
Beyond that,
it's better to try lightly immoral business practices as a kid!
One more time!
Locchi!
If you try them when you grow up, it'll be too late.
Does anyone want to buy some detergent?
Anyway,
late-onset measles are troublesome!
Teacher.
Who are you?
I'm a freshman from the next school over.
Love
I love you
You've gotten popular, teacher.
Chikuwa Club
W-What are you saying!?
Isn't female students falling for their teacher a kind of measles?
Measles!
If we don't get them...
Measles!  Measles!
Teacher, I've found a way to get out of coming to school legally!
Also, to deceive more female students!
Whisper whisper.
I see!
Aji-oh Culinary Group
Oh my.  This class is pretty quiet.
Chikuwa Club
Class canceled
Class is canceled. Due to measles.
Night Watch Room
I don't think this solves the root of the problem.
It's the other way around. If someone who's gonna become a teacher isn't immunized,
he'll go for the female students when he becomes one!
I caught the real thing...
Chiri's Lecture on Playing Alone
It's better to play meat doll when you're little.
If you do it once you've grown up, your friends will be bigger too,
and you'll need lots of kite string and raw meat.
And if the neighbors see you, the effect will likely be lost.
What the hell are you playing!?
How to play
Meat doll
Author: Kitsu Chiri
How to play meat doll!
First, cover a friend in meat!
Next, tie them with kite string!
Leave them in the
sun for three days!
Next, tie them with kite string!
Leave them in the sun for three days!
Leave them in the
sun for three days!
When they're done, beat the
pigeons away and play!
Leave them in the
sun for three days!
When they're done, beat the pigeons away and play!
When they're done, beat the
pigeons away and play!
Fin
When they're done, beat the
pigeons away and play!
Workers are beautiful
Oh, this is
Oora's house.
Oora
Workers are
beautiful
Japan Labor Party
Is this the political party Oora supports?
Nippori
It sure seems that way.
Workers are
beautiful
Japan Labor Party
Workers are
beautiful
Japan Labor Party
Certainly in
Opposition
Communist  Party
Hi!
Mind if I post this?
Sure!
It's fine, go right ahead!
Can I post this?
Go ahead.
Nippori
Seems like it's just an open-hearted, magnanimous household.
Musashi-Koyama Shopping District High
So... I was thinking,
why not increase the number of points?
Net
Blog
Game
Comic
Novel
Anime
Originally published 15th October, Showa 83.
From Chapter 157
Polygon in the Evening
Why not increase the number of points?
Nami
If there aren't enough points, things get prickly!
With just you and one other point, a sharp, piercing spear is formed.
Self
By adding more points, it becomes smooth,
unpiercing, unprickly.
For example, by only placing posters for one party, things become noisy.
Glory
to You,
the
Worker
Super Labor Party
But by putting up plenty of them, you're simply thought of as an open-hearted person.
Even for cults!
If there's just one, things get prickly,
but if there's plenty, no one worries!
Cult
People think each one isn't -too- bad.
If you have a complex about one thing, it'll be attacked.
Baldy
Baldy!
But if you have four or five, no one will say anything!
If you were wearing clothes, you'd just be a trespasser.
But if you're naked, it's too easy to crack jokes and no one gets angry!
Die
Oh no!
Meru's abusive language has pierced Teacher!
It's just one insult, so it's piercing.
Die
trash bug
garbage
shit
bald
moron
If there were five or six, it wouldn't be prickly.
This is horrible in and of itself!
But each individual word hurts less.
Really, in some country somewhere, there are far more insulting words than there are in Japanese.
Since you're insulted even as a greeting, none of them really matter.
Japanese History B
I see.
By adding points, society won't loathe me anymore.
Harumi
Japanese
History B
Harumi
Japanese
History B
Like this!
Melting Into You
BL as a group
No, that's only one point.
I thought I put in plenty of variations!
From society's viewpoint, it's all the same.
Well, I guess if people don't realize it's no good.
It's something where you tried to add points, but ended up with only one!
That's right, it was a great loss!
Even though they were promoted as diversified investments to spread risk!
The entire world has been routed due to the panic!
Dow
Dollars
Asian shares
European shares
Simultaneous drop
Nikkei index
Ultimately, the investments were a single point!
How many times are they going to have to stop the Chuo line today!?
Well, let's leave discussions which are too realistic behind for now.
Nutrition is like that too.
I put my heart into keeping a balance.
Sweet
Cream
Donuts
Snacks
Anko
Ice cream
Chocolate
No, that's completely off-center.
Anyway.
Things become less prickly when you add points!
Love triangles are like that too.
If there's three points, things are prickly.
Love
That may very well be true.
Peace
Maria
world of manga
Like this, the points quickly become piercing.
Wife
plus
But like this, it's a bit smoother.
Chikuwa Club
The “Cats Card” has four points!
But even with four points it's still prickly!
To smooth over the prickliness, we need more and more points!
Otherwise the class will become bloodthirsty!
Really!?
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry!  I'm sorry!
Wife
More and more points!
Sixth point!
6th point
Seventh point!
7th point
Eighth point!
th point
Ninth point!
Tenth point!
Eleventh point!
th point
Twelfth point!
Thirteenth point!
th point
Fourteenth point!
By adding more and more points,
the polygon will become infinitely close to being a circle,
and mankind will be at peace!
Chiri, you too!
You're unusually cheerful.
Second
"Where's
Sanosuke?"
recruiting
assistants
Really.
No damn way.
Adding more women makes things less prickly?
The hell are you, Ishida Jun'ichi!?
I knew it!
The hell are you, Morimoto Leo!?
Looks like the points are still pointy.
You still don't have enough relationships with different women!
Isn't it strange?
By adding more points, will I be freed from this unspeakable horror?
Second
"Where's
Sanosuke?"
Get more relationships with people in town!
Free hugs
How many are you up to now?
I'm in about a 53-way relationship!
It's almost a circle!
Soon, the world will be at peace!
Are you a fool?
The more women you get, the heavier your sins become.
With this kind of circle—!
Teacher, your theory was refuted!
It was half yours, wasn't it!?
If I just use my spade, it'll be prickly,
so to be milder,
I've added points.
Weapon
That's just one point!
I'll borrow one.
Me too.
Sorry I'm late.
All right.
Isn't she concerned about this?
She's a magnanimous girl.
Class register #16
Oora Kanako
Magnanimous girl
Anyway, I keep picturing all these little kids playing some game in this big field of rye and all.
Thousands of little kids kids, and nobody's around - nobody big, I mean - except me.
And I'm standing on the edge of some crazy cliff.
What I have to do, I have
to catch everybody if they
start to go over the cliff
- I mean if they're running
and they don't look where
they're going I have to
come out from somewhere
and catch them.
That's all I do all day. I'd just be the catcher in the rye and all.
I know it's crazy, but that's the only thing I'd really like to be.
Originally published 8th August, Showa 82.
From Chapter 105
The Dropper in the Rye
Part 2
Oh, teacher.
Through life?
Butcher
It's a kind lifestyle where you ignore many things.
Didn't we use this same kind of gag a long time ago?
Ignore that too.
Teacher, it looks like you finally get through life!
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Haneka Books
Super Under Through
Clearance
Tientiensu
You mean like what we just did?
It's not that bad. I think I'll try it out.
Drugs
Golden Ginza Shopping District
Ignoring that.
Moved
due to
circum-
stances
Moved
due to
circum-
stances
Pastoral
Definitely ignoring that.
World Paripari Value
World Baribari Value
Rich Comickers
Ignoring that.
I'm ignoring them all!
If you put it that way, I'm experiencing through life too.
Ohkusa?
Inbox
Hi, this is Yuki. Thanks
for today. Let's hang
out again.
<(^o^)>
Reply
Select
Function
Even though I know it, I ignore when my husband's horny.
I don't have the money to go to hospital, so I ignore pains.
I ignore N-bleep-K's demands for money.
If I don't ignore them, I wouldn't be able to go on with my daily life!
Clearance
Tientiensu
I don't know how to put this, but I'm sorry for ignoring things as a hobby.
Didn't you
just hit
something!?
Why don't you just ignore that?
Famous sweets
Tokyo Ma
Drugstore
Drugs
Flor
A hit-and-run!?
Drugstore
Yoshi-
moto
No way.  There's no way a hit-and-run would happen right in front of us.
He's just ignoring things that happen while driving.
You could call it a “drive through”.
Are you trying to be clever!?
Teacher!  Chiri's starting to thoroughly place “made by” labels!
Haga Books
Mari+Holi
Es
Ef
Hold★It
I drew this.
What's this!?
It's a “made by” label.
Haga Books
Mari+Holi
Es
Ef
I grew these
Just picked 'em, here you go!
Uonuma's
-grown.
Nowadays, it's normal to be able to see who grew your veggies!
Let's make it so you can see the faces of the people who made everything!
Knock it off!  You'll crush dreams!
No!
Oh, hey, Chiri.
Who made -you-?
This is too horrible!
Tofu
It's like the faux pas a middle-schooler would make.
A
SHAFT traced the
backs that I drew.
All right, I'll make it so you can see the faces of the people who made everything!
There!
Umm... On this picture of my parents, you got my dad wrong...
We made him.
The one who made you doesn't care.
What!?
You're wrong, Chiri.
All people are children of God!
Are you on about Balbora the Third again!?
That's who made you.
Since Japan is the land of myriad gods,
each person was made by a different god.
Is this my Creator?
Who!?
Those are god stickers that came with chocolate bars.
Brother, the manufacturing line is in full operation!
Itoshiki
God-Choco
Sado
Kagawa
It's like it prints money!
Doesn't this mean we're accomplices in selling trinkets?
Here's a rare card!
Master Jealous
God Card
There's a total of 81!
Gotta catch 'em all!
Shall we make you happy?  Find your way to our door
Welcome to our grand reopening
Our clothing clings precariously to our shoulders
For now, forget everyday life
Wipe off the night dew and come in
A still-beating heart?  Blue, and done rare?
It fits well with what you really mean
Poison and lies become our habitual spices
Stick a fork in your unsatisfied sadness
It's fine if you leave what you don't like, just like a child
It'll cheer you up, make you feel better bite by bite
I wave and smile, saying "see you next week"
One-night-only cash
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Fujibayashi Kyo,
Kamio Misuzu, Furukawa Nagisa, Ibuki Fuko,
Ichinose Kotomi, Sakagami Tomoyo, Great
Shocker Party, or god stickers which may go
on sale in the future is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou  Sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
.
Matching the song, let's draw with a G-pen, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
.
Lightning...
...
Flash!
!
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
!
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Matsuki Miyu
Inoue Marina
?
Bye bye!
!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:
Hayashiya Shizuru
Let's despair over the next volume too!