The story until now.
With a single word by Leah Dizon, the Nishiogi-Kubo International Film Festival was opened.
To the folks who insisted it was a "paradise of cinema",
those who planned to revitalize a village with anime were not interesting at all.
With grudging, forced consent, taking a megaphone and caught in a veritable honey trap,
they became enveloped in a rampant love like that felt by a modern girlie-girl maiden in Uno Chiyo.
As a result, on the false pretense that the first kanji in the word "delusion" is insulting to women,
they were told "Love Confessions, Love Confessions!" in Fujin bleep-ron,
the shameful love confession of having their nipples covered in syrup and then being buried in an anthill.
At that moment, with the single word "Cut!", Mizuno Haruo, dressed as an American policeman, appeared.
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Your life changes everything
It's just as you think
Even if I find someone singing
I can't fall in love right away
Maybe just not at work
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
Apple!
Picking!
Beam!
But since
you can't
stop your
thoughts
Believe
And
Yell out the password
That everything
Will change
If we sing together
Change
Fly
I'm flying
Who do you want to show this new you?
To the guy that slighted me!
Let's go
A little bit of despair
Over to this side
It's Shangri-la for sure
If it's with you,
That's the
password
APPLE!
Picking!
Beam!
But no matter where I go
It's always the same
You're always there
Waiting for me
Iba Shogyo High
2-VI
Oora! It's already next week!
Exhibition sales
Eurian
Deposit sales
Futures sales
Furniture lease sales
Date sales
Originally published 20th October, Showa 83.
From Chapter 158
Do Androids Dream of Electric Wives?
She's been there since the week before last.
Such a placid girl.
I've been treated so horribly these past two weeks.
Teacher.
Chilly ice
Now retailing
Hey.
Oh, teacher!
How about one?
A
2-VI  Class roster #26
Nedu    Miko
Ice
\10000
Ice for ¥10,000?
There's no way it'll sell at that price.
You won't buy any?
Isono
Not at all.
Maguro
Direct
sales
Maguro
Direct
sales
Hey.
Oh, teacher!
How about some?
A
2-VI  Class roster #30
Maruuchi    Shouko
Maguro-style lean tuna
blog
What a bargain!
I'll buy, I'll buy!
Sold
out.
Thanks!
This was a good deal.
Suddenly, fierce solar rays!?
It's going bad before my eyes!
No matter where I dodge to, the solar rays follow me!
I'll have to buy ice at a nearby convenience store!
The closest one is a ten-minute walk.
Oh no, my maguro's gonna rot! What do I do!?
Chilly ice
Teacher.
Ice
\10000
Sold!
Chilly ice
Thanks!
All right! That's a load off my back!
Chilly ice
Thanks a lot!
Sports car
moved by
wrecker
Isono
Like that, huh?
Perfect.
You're great. Well done.
A
Kainan University
Affiliated High School
Total
Oh man!
Why did you waste money like this!?
It's strange, isn't it.
Sure, the maguro was a pretty good find,
but you can't spend ten thousand yen on a block of ice!
That's what's called a loss leader.
It's a common business model.
You were there?
Always.
For example, printers.
High-performance
The units themselves are really cheap now.
But in exchange, the ink's expensive.
So they make their profit off the ink?
That's right. There are other examples, too.
Hair-growth trial
You too!
1000 hairs
free!!
Wow!
For more information
call 0120-HIR-SUTE
After growing your thousand free hairs, you can't go back
and will spend incredible amounts of money!
\1 to start
Contract
Copiers and stuff are bought incredibly cheap,
Koishikawa
ward office
maintenance
\100,000
and the profit is made on the maintenance!
There really are a lot of things like that.
When you buy into a timeshare as a matter of course
That's cheap!
We'll take it!
but the maintenance fees are ¥100,000 a month and you have to take out a loan, is the same!
Maintenance fee
\100,000 monthly
Dr. **rton is free for three months,
Internet Security
Dr. **rton
Academic
Warning
Your computer is infected.
Buy **rton
Don't buy
but then he warns you constantly of the dangers you would face witout him, and you buy it!
I'm in despair!
Businesses which make up the money later have left me in despair!
The two of you...
Bourgeois
First issue
Weekly
Each issue comes with parts
Chiwagostini
My
Iron Man
This week
Awesome right ankle
First issue
Weekly
Each issue comes with parts
Chiwagostini
My
Iron Man
This week
Awesome right ankle
Aim to complete it!
First issue
Weekly
Each issue comes with parts
Chiwagostini
My
Iron Man
This week
Awesome right ankle
Aim to complete it!
Wasting your allowance again, Majiru?
It's not a waste! This thing's great!
Every issue comes with parts!
vol. 2
left leg
vols. 7–10
strong-looking right arm
vols. 51–56
head
Put them all together, and it makes a combining robot!
final volume
remote control
Gattai!
And every issue is only ¥190!
Isn't it a value!
Starting next issue, it's ¥500.
That really is the same marketing.
I was caught by it, too.
“Weekly Travel Pack”.
Weekly Travel Pack
Includes
one-way
ticket
Enough to get you to Hades!
First issue
Weekly Travel Pack
Includes one-way ticket
Buy every issue, and at the end, you'll go on a journey.
Volume 1 was “bath beads A”, volume 2 was “bath beads B”.
Being able to go on a journey in only two weeks...
Well, it is pretty honest.
I see.
Now that I think of it, Teacher is pretty popular with the girls.
JZU
Cage
Weekly             Cardigan & Muffler
Weekly             St. Clare's
Weekly             Big Brother
Weekly             Absolute Boyfriend
Chiwagostini
Weekly                             Cardigan & Muffler
Weekly                              St. Clare's
Weekly                             My Big Brother
Weekly                              Absolute Boyfriend
Chiwagostini
Heavy Equipment - Construction Equipment Data File
Weekly Space Genesis
Weekly Adamski
Weekly World Ooparts
Build Your Own Panjandrum
This is—
Haven't your portions been a bit small lately?
It's because you've wasted your money, Majiru.
I haven't wasted that much.
If you don't like it, I won't make anything for you.
Cage
She's been acting funny lately.
I wonder if she's not wasting her money on something.
Chiwagostini
Weekly Zetsubou-sensei
First issue: Head
Buy them
all, and get!
This is—!
"Every month comes with human body parts! Put them together, and in the end, you'll have Zetsubou-sensei!”?
A
Hand
Torso and waist use
revolver-style joints.
Can be posed freely!
With “multi-material construction”,
all five fingers have both full motion and form.
A new type of joint
construction that clicks
firmly into place.  Holds
fabulous action poses.
Zetsubou-sensei (complete)
Glasses cast
off
I'm in despair!
Warning:
if joints are forcefully bent,
the surface may crack.
Ankle joints revised for
sure footing.
Magnets are installed
in the soles of the
feet. Stands freely.
Characteristic
hairstyle repro-
duced realistically.
Double-jointed
elbows
Skin made of
cloth for reali-
stic feeling
“Revolver-style joints”:
Out of order
To Save
Weekly Sayonara, Zetsubou-sensei
Chiwagostini
Weekly Zetsubou
Parts
Internal
organs
Out of order
Oh no! Kiri's gonna kill me!
What's up, Majiru?
Just what is this...
What's the meaning of this?
Unfortunately, Itoshiki Nozomu, you have already died once in a mysterious explosion.
See?
The contents of your brain have been programmed into an AI,
and the scientific talents of shut-ins across the land have come together to revive you as an android!
Don't you know the Three Laws of Robotics?
You must absolutely obey the orders of your creator!
All right, this is the final part.
The tabi?
Oh no, I've gotta hide!
All right.
“Just after completion, it will act as the creator wills...”, huh?
Kiss me.
Three Laws of Robotics
Abso
lute
Obedi
ence
No way! I'm such a fool!
Third Law of Robotics
Abso
lute
Obedi
ence
What am I making my creation do!?
I take that back. Go clean the gutters.
And this is...?
Third “Where's
Sanosuke?” over
I told you, I got tired of it after the first issue!
Class register #26
Nedu Miko
Class register #30
Maruuchi Shouko
Infinite sales
chain girls
It's chilly.
... Nope, not really.
This winter has been really mild.
There's someone passed out!
He's—!
General Frost!
What, outta money after moving to a new office!?
Gotta cut corners to make a profit, huh!?
Your production costs are the same but other companies are selling a lot better!
You really can't pull this off at the same time as Ghostory, can you!
The pictures aren't moving!  You can't even call this animation!
The anime industry's collapsing!
Originally published 14th February, Showa 82.
From Chapter 83
Failure as a General
General Frost!
He's General Frost!
He's so weak!
General Frost is a person!?
I thought it was the Siberian cold air mass!
Siberian cold-air mass
A low-volume , dry
air mass that lingers
over Siberia as fall
turns to winter.
One of the Frigid
Zone continental air masses.
With General Frost this weak, winters will be mild.
Don't be so solemn while lying!
He's a person of high status, so let's hospitably bring him to the classroom.
A
Shoyo High School
2-VI
Furinkazan
General
How fare thee, milord?
Been better.
Well, it's summer
If General Frost ends up like that, ski areas and the leggings industry will be inconvenienced.
Inconvenienced
Meat buns
Cup shiruko
toilets
Kerosene
Hand warmers
Fat
Yuming
Honestly...
I've been thinking of quitting as General Frost.
What are you saying!? Were you to quit, Hirose Komi would be crestfallen!
But with this winter so mild, you can't really call him General Frost, can you?
More like Colonel Frost.
Colonel? Colonel!?
My eyes!
I can't see!
What are you saying, Kitsu!?
To soldiers, rank is more important than their lives!
General
Your rank will follow it down.
To be honest, that's it.
I want to stop being General Frost, but not stop being a general.
That's right.
Once you've experienced being a general, you can't be anything else.
All right, let's go to Hello Work and see if they're hiring generals!
Came because I saw the recruitment poster
Hello Work
Koishikawa
Anywhere hiring generals?
Applicant Interview
There ain't nothing.
Recruiting employees
Depressed
country
President wanted
Recruiting governor.
Open-
ings
Free
Please use
next window
I'm okay with being a General Rowdy or a demon general, instead.
There's no way you can go from being General Frost to a demon general.
Yeah, I guess.
Recruiting
employees
Oompa-loompa
3x the cocoa beans
Wolka
Aruaru Cup
Hiring now!
The freedom
to select
your career
Ahahaaan
DET News
The
battle for a
career is
heating up
Crab General is looking for potential managers.
Crab Shogun
Ah, here's one! A pro baseball team general!
Tokyo
Worker
Baseball?
Koishikawa Public Baseball Stadium
We need a pitcher, not a belly-itcher!
A heckling general!?
Hey, the outfielders are gonna catch a cold!
With that kind of heckling, I can't call you a heckling general at all.
More like heckling colonel.
Again!?
Colonel...Colonel again...
Take care
of the bases.
-Brown
Riben Ham
Maishu News
Frozen
Yamashita
You're stirring things up again!
But like that,
he isn't even fit to lick the boots of the legendary Hecklers General!
Don't you even know the basics of baseball!?
I did it a few times with the party leader!
Your sister's an xxx!
Don't just send me weaklings!
Foods
Then what kind of heckling is general-class?
Well, for example...
That's cruel!
Telling Hichori he'll “never win any smiles alone” is too much!
Hold it!
You're so troublesome!
How!?
To draw properly?
Sannoh Industry Affiliated High School
I knew it, I can't handle being a heckling general.
We can get away with it nowadays, so why not just tack “General” onto anything?
It's not **nzo, so
it's not embarrassing!
For example...
Love General!
Love...General.
Love General. That's nice.
Love General is pretty good!
I've decided! I'll become a Love General!
Twoce!
What's this “Love General” thing, anyway!?
But if you become a Love General, you've got to have general-class loves.
Loves worthy of a general?
Basquash!
Somehow, that's a horrible image.
I quit being a Love General.
Then how about being a Dream General?
Dream General?
I can do that!
Hope we make it in time for broadcast
I have dreams worthy of a general!
A private car
A private home (with garden)
\1,000,000
Hitting the lotto for ¥60,000,000
Those are the dreams of commoners!
The archetypal ones!
You're not cut out to be a Dream General.
I see.
Lately, the word “Dream” has had a lot of trouble associated with it, so you should probably quit.
Okay, I'll do that.
Reconciled
Other generals, huh. Oh, that's right.
Comics General.
General Metabolic
Miss General
General Shi-bleep Kosaku
General NEET
How about these?
What kind of general is that!?
If we're just making up names, I'd like to try being a general too.
Really?
Comics General.
Don't call me a Comics General!
That isn't praise at all, is it!? You're not praising me at all, are you!?
Sweat-drenched Comiket
Salty
Now, everyone is calling themselves a general!
(at home)
Why does ‘Normal General’ seem like the best one?
Fleeing General
Because it's normal?
Don't call me normal!
Let's give everyone the prestige of being called General!
That just isn't the same, is it!?
Middle-part
I've got to make a part straight down the middle worth of a general.
General
Middle-part
Is she trying to split the earth in two!?
Someone please stop her!
There's no one higher-ranking than a general enough to voice their opinion.
There's one person.
Who!?
Who can give orders to a general!?
Emperor Penguin.
A
Emperor Penguin
Aptenodytes
forsteri
Penguin family
Emperor
penguin genus
Inhabits the coasts of Antarctica
Largest of the living penguins
As you will.
Because it's an emperor penguin!?
Night Watch Room
Which is more eminent, an emperor or a general?
An emperor is far more eminent.
You did great.
Someday, I hope to be Emperor Frost.
This's long!
2-VI
From Class 2-VI
Happy Birthday
Happy birthday!
From Class 2-VI
Happy birthday, teacher!
Happy Birthday
Were you surprised?
It's a surprise party.
Shocked that there were still no storyboards on editing day
Shocked that the art wasn't done by ADR day
Shocked that dubbing got pushed back a week
Shocked that some cuts weren't done on delivery day
Shocked that we finished the video on broadcast day
Shocked that it actually broadcast at the normal time
Originally published 17th September, Showa 83.
From Chapter 152
Yeah, it's a surprise,
I muttered hollowly
That's definitely a surprise!
After all, today isn't my birthday.
Right, it's in November, isn't it?
Itoshiki Nozomo
b. November 4th
So why do it today!?
Didn't you tell us, teacher?
A few days prior
“Plenty of Earthquakes” High
I thought I'd have a surprise birthday party for a friend later.
Surprise?
How is a birthday party on someone's birthday a surprise!?
So...
It seems like something I'd say, and I feel like I've said it.
I want to be with a guy, and always have my heart going pitter-patter.
And from time to time, I'd like surprises.
Girls are like that.
Annoying!
Whose internal monologue was that!?
No one thinks that!
I don't think you're annoying.
I don't think so. I don't think you're boring at all.
All of them!?
Well, nowadays, even if you don't go looking for them there are plenty of day-to-day surprises in this world.
The surprise of throwing out a PM between elections twice in a row!
Different
from you
September
The surprise of finding out right before that this time your deadline's a day early!
Finding out that after ten years that your rice was blended with contaminated rice!
That's surprice!
Rice
The shock of getting together and finding out that everyone at the party decided to bring a horn!
That's a real surprise party!
Those last two are putting a bit too much of a spin on it.
There are so many no-good surprises!
Japanese can't be shocked by small things anymore!
That's too bad.
We weren't able to give teacher a surprise party just by changing the date.
Well, it's the thought that counts.
But it's a bit different from a surprise.
Chiri, I was right, it wasn't a surprise.
Hold it...
Didn't I tell you?
Connected
Chiri
The real surprise party starts now.
No, I've had enough surprises for now!
What is this!?
Let's start the surprise party.
And shock teacher with things like a Communist bazaar and a raw meat tasting!
You were all surprised, right?
Well...
It wasn't a surprise at all.
No, I was plenty surprised!
I thought of several other ways to appear, too.
Appearing from inside!
Appearing in the sky!
Appearing out of someone's pocket!
Well, it's you, Chiri, so no matter what you do, I'm not really surprised.
It's the other way around. If you didn't do anything, just held a normal birthday party, I'd be surprised.
That'd be surprising.
What do you mean!?
It may be more common in modern Japan to be surprised if something isn't done.
Marui, I want to talk with you about something, so can we meet up after class?
What do I do!? My heart isn't ready!
To be continued
Shall we make you happy?  Find your way to our door
Welcome to our grand reopening
Our clothing clings precariously to our shoulders
For now, forget everyday life
Wipe off the night dew and come in
A still-beating heart?  Blue, and done rare?
It fits well with what you really mean
Poison and lies become our habitual spices
Stick a fork in your unsatisfied sadness
It's fine if you leave what you don't like, just like a child
It'll cheer you up, make you feel better bite by bite
I wave and smile, saying "see you next week"
One-night-only cash
This is a work of fiction.
Similarity to any actual Zanda Cross, Hichori, or PM Fukuda is purely coincidental.
Zetsubou  Sensei
Drawing  Song
Written  by:  Hisamoto  Natsu
The Zetsubou-sensei Drawing Song is about to start.
Matching the song, let's draw together, okay?
A tulip leans in the wind, and lays flat.
Lightning...
Flash!
The rain comes pouring down.
From the gaps came the leaks.
Two puddles were made.
Let's go fishing, there's the fish hook!
With the fish we caught, we made a fish cake.
It's Zetsubou-sensei!
It's done!!
neya michiko
Did everyone draw well?
Illustrated by
Horie Yui
Neya Michiko
Bye bye!
WITH MY
STEPMOTHER
FIN
By the ZBC
Illustration:
Shimura Takako
Let's despair over the next volume too!